<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Issue 05: Catharsis on Cicada Creative Magazine</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/issues/issue-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Issue 05: Catharsis on Cicada Creative Magazine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 02:03:11 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/issues/issue-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: Revise and Resubmit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/introducing-revise-and-resubmit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 17:21:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/introducing-revise-and-resubmit/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re piloting a Revise &amp;amp; Resubmit process! This post goes into more detail about what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue 08 Deadline Extension</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/deadline-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 18:18:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/deadline-extension/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone! We&amp;rsquo;re hard at work reviewing your submissions, and we want to thank you for entrusting us with your work. To ensure we are delivering you the absolute best issue we can, we had a meeting and decided it would be best to extend this issue cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance Pranks and Protest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/renaissance-pranks-and-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 15:53:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/renaissance-pranks-and-protest/</guid>
      <description>Those who remember their art history know that the great Renaissance sculptor, Michelangelo, was reluctant to paint the Sistine Chapel. What they might not remember is that this complicated story between Mike and Pope Julius II resulted in the Renaissance’s greatest prank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrations in Spring: Bookish Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/celebrations-in-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 15:51:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/celebrations-in-spring/</guid>
      <description>An ambling sun. Budding flora. A wind, quiet and placid, welcoming you into spring. More than the bearer of the new season, March is National Reading Month, making it a double invitation for the revitalization of our joy and energy. Accept the invitation and cherish life’s vivacity through a celebration of books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reintroducing Ourselves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reintroducing-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 15:04:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/reintroducing-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>Cicada has evolved a lot over the years. This isn’t the first time I’ve said this, and it won’t be the last, but I want to focus on explaining where we are rather than how we got here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Penpals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/21st-century-penpals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 20:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/21st-century-penpals/</guid>
      <description>As the thrill of starting a new year fizzles out and Valentine’s Day approaches, it’s a good time to think about the ways we communicate with the people in our lives, and maybe even try something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with Penny Molesso</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/an-interview-with-penny-molesso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 20:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/an-interview-with-penny-molesso/</guid>
      <description>Penny is a transmedia artist, filmaker, and writer whose vision for interdisciplinarity resonates with our own. We caught them and decided to ask a few questions about their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCM Updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ccm-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 13:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ccm-updates/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve made it no secret that CCM is an ever-evolving project, and we&amp;rsquo;ve always believed it&amp;rsquo;s important to be transparent with you all. This post will break down some of the changes you can expect to see from CCM this issue cycle, like rolling reviews (which means shorter response time), staff restructuring, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When in Crisis, Get a Plant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-in-crisis-get-a-plant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:51:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-in-crisis-get-a-plant/</guid>
      <description>When work stress, family drama, and traffic nightmares follow you home, scientists and gardeners agree on one solution &amp;ndash; get a houseplant. A wide variety of studies describe the effect green plants have in classrooms, hospitals, offices, and especially homes. Overall, the presence of two to five growing things in your living space will improve your well being. The effects are most profound in children and young adults, as well as any person experiencing low mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Eats - Flowers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/edible-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:31:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/edible-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Edible flowers have been on the menu for humans since the beginning of our gastronomical explorations. But in recent years, they’ve begun appearing in our appetizers, on our dinner plates, and in our desserts as well. Some are much more than just garnishes for salads and cocktails, and may even offer health benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parasite: Spatial Dynamics created through Architecture and Film</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/parasite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 16:24:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/parasite/</guid>
      <description>An exploration of spatial dynamics created between architecture and film narratives. How do director Bong Joon Ho and production designer Lee Ha Jun craft the relationship between the Park family home and the characters of Parasite?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Is for Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/spring-is-for-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:51:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/spring-is-for-action/</guid>
      <description>Spring is when we all come back to life after our long winter hibernation state and it’s just in time to help us recover from the daylight savings shift that nearly made it nearly impossible to defrost ourselves. It’s a time when art starts to feel sweeter and the colors engulf us in happiness and allergies. Spring also comes with the not-so-popular municipal elections which are often under-hyped in states all across the country. There’s a reason our elections take such a long break from November to April and it isn’t because of the temperature changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap: What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Our Discord server got a makeover, we have the beginnings of some proper documentation, polls for Issue 07&amp;rsquo;s theme are live, and staff applications are open! But there&amp;rsquo;s lots more coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back! Issue 06 and moving forward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/were-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 22:19:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/were-back/</guid>
      <description>First things first&amp;ndash;go read &lt;a href=&#34;../../issues/issue-6/&#34;&gt;Issue 06&lt;/a&gt;! It&amp;rsquo;s great and everyone worked really hard on it. But I wanted to use this chance to explain our unannounced hiatus, what we learned during it, and what&amp;rsquo;s next for CCM. (Spoiler, submissions will be opening for everyone!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redecorate your Room! Find Your Inspo from 8 pieces of Interior Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/redecorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 23:00:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/redecorate/</guid>
      <description>The way a room is decorated can have everything to do with how you feel when you are in it. Blue painted walls might evoke feelings of tranquility and peace. For some, it might make them feel melancholy. Artists have been able to express the different types of beauty and feelings that are brought on from colors, shapes, and designs in interior design. Explore these 8 interior related art pieces to find what rooms you resonate emotionally with best, but also to gain inspiration for a new look to your room!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrology in Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/astrology-in-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 22:52:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/astrology-in-art/</guid>
      <description>Astrology today is, I hate to say it, a bit of a joke. It makes you think of Buzzfeed and CO-Sign and while all that&amp;rsquo;s well and good, they don’t have any sizable impact on your livelihood (or at least I hope not).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Disjointed Creative Communal Isolation: The Plight of the Quarantined Creative Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/communal-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 22:46:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/communal-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Art in isolation isn’t a new concept, many artists feel as though the isolation opens the creative mind allowing for a comprehensive connection to their work that supersedes the need for community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gothic Influence in Horror Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gothic-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 22:32:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/gothic-horror/</guid>
      <description>Gothic art may make you think of poorly painted Medieval friezes, but this spooky season, let’s think about another form of Gothic art. Art inspired by the themes of Gothic fiction, also known as Gothic Horror. Read more to see the work of 6 talented artists who evoke the Gothic themes of sadness, fear, and terror in their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Guess We’ll Never Know: Ambiguous Endings in Horror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ambiguous-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ambiguous-endings/</guid>
      <description>The best horror movies have ambiguous endings. Endings that make you leave confused, in disbelief, and searching the internet for more details and answers. The movie remains in your head, and you’re stuck thinking, what happens next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Healthy Escapism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/escapism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:06:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/escapism/</guid>
      <description>Escapism gets a bad rap, understandably so. It’s often perceived as someone running away from their feelings by refusing to engage with reality&amp;ndash;an unhealthy coping mechanism. Conventional wisdom says that the Right Way™ to deal with negative emotions is to feel all of it and work through the weeds of it. Maybe you talk it out with friends, have a good cry, or draw a bubble bath. I’ve tried all that. It makes me feel worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margin Doodles of a Monster Named Stress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/margin-doodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 21:06:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/margin-doodles/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes stress can take hold of you, reaching its withering hands around your body, plucking at your heartstrings like it’s playing guitar. If you’re like me (unprepared and disorganized), then the beginning of the school year can be particularly stressful. The stress monster can linger at the corner of your eyes, fading into a haze when you try to look at it head on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fill! Your! Pages!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/fill-your-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 22:19:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/fill-your-pages/</guid>
      <description>Finishing something you worked really hard on might just be one of the best feelings in the world. But what makes this accomplishment feel even more fulfilling? When you planned every step of the way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Cicada are you?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/cicada-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 22:12:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/cicada-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Made for fun! Brought to you by Cicada Creative Magazine. CW // photos of bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is art boundary-breaking if it’s stolen?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/boundary-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 22:07:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/boundary-breaking/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re back in high school, working on a group project with the artsy philosophy guy who exclusively talks back to his female teachers. The project requires you to bring in some sort of family heirloom from home to share with your partner and then present to the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That time Andy Warhol plagiarized Yayoi Kusama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/warhol-kusama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 22:03:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/warhol-kusama/</guid>
      <description>If you asked a stranger to list any 5 artists off the top of their head, odds are good that Andy Warhol would be one of them. A soup can homage even sits in front of CSU’s Center for the Arts (to honor a visit from Warhol in 1981). There is no doubt that his contributions altered the trajectory of American art. He also copied part of one of Yayoi Kusama’s exhibitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in punk!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/punk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 21:59:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/punk/</guid>
      <description>The Punk Movement was largely male-dominated, as much of the music industry is, but the women of Punk embodied the movement wholly and didn&amp;rsquo;t receive adequate credit. The movement’s female artists highlighted the struggles of the female experience that didn&amp;rsquo;t fit into the mainstream narrative. In their focus on anger and style of dressing, the women of the Punk Movement pushed back against societal norms more effectively than the more popular male bands could.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Love Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:57:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/love-story/</guid>
      <description>Agh, February! The month of love. This month I was determined to present you all with a love story—cliché, I know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Swamp Inspired Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:51:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/swamp/</guid>
      <description>I love wildlife. I have ever since I was a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Tattoo Artists That Make Me Want to Cover My Skin in Ink</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tattoo-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:43:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tattoo-artists/</guid>
      <description>In my many years as a creative-driven being, I’ve discovered that I have a great affinity for tattoo art. Tattoo practice is something that is taboo in our society because of its permanence. However, tattoo artists are just as credible as other artists, and their art is worthy of admiration and respect! Especially because there is much effort and tireless work that goes into being a professional tattoo artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring ugly babies across art history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ugly-babies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 21:16:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ugly-babies/</guid>
      <description>Anyone visiting an art museum or studying art history has probably encountered a weirdly shaped baby at some point in their life. These long-limbed babies, resembling a small man or wrinkly sock puppet, are a common staple of art from the Middle Ages all the way up into the Renaissance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Arbitrary Ways to Stay Creative at Home </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/7-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 21:13:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/7-ways/</guid>
      <description>It’s 2021, and COVID is still in full swing. With cities encouraging us to continue social distancing, work from home and limit our activity outside of the home, it can be hard to stay entertained and feel motivated. At this point we have all moved on from whipped coffee and sourdough bread, so here are 10 other ideas on how to be creative at home!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature is out there! (and it can help with your health and creativity, too!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:10:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/nature/</guid>
      <description>With all the craziness that 2020 has brought, it can be difficult to  remember to take some time to care for yourself. Luckily, I am here to  inform you that one of the easiest ways to do so is remarkably simple&amp;ndash;spend some time outside!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Sincerity during Quarantine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-sincerity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:07:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-sincerity/</guid>
      <description>Art  changes throughout time, evolving to address each century’s unique  struggles and values. In an effort to retaliate against the cynicism of a  post-war era, modern writers began to pioneer a new age of writing  which they called New Sincerity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss Being a Kid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/being-a-kid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:01:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/being-a-kid/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes  college is the place where we lose it—it not referring to virginity,  house keys, parental respect, or mental stability. Hard as it is to  admit, I myself have lost it more than once here, despite the fact that  I’ve spent a lot of money to become an undergrad and curate it, in hopes  of making it marketable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Montage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/modern-montage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:59:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/modern-montage/</guid>
      <description>Protest  has also been a prevalent theme in art throughout the years. This  timeline explores art that addresses injustice and inequality in the  past 100 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small social elements of the classroom that I miss, a comic.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/social-elements-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:34:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/social-elements-classroom/</guid>
      <description>I miss sitting in front of a real person and hearing them lecture, but even more than that I miss the ten minutes before class where I could talk to my peers, catch up on current world news, and orient myself with where everyone else was in their projects (was I behind?). I’ve had no trouble getting access to lectures and asking questions through zoom, but I miss the sense of community formed by a classroom joke. Education is such a social thing, which virtual education just can’t replicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proctoring software is a nightmare for students. It doesn’t have to be this way.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/proctoring-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:28:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/proctoring-software/</guid>
      <description>As you all know, COVID. In response to the lack of in-person interaction, many colleges and universities have begun to use proprietary software to ensure students do not cheat during exams, most often ProctorU, Proctorio, and ExamSoft. I take 3 issues with this development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Brief History of Protest Art in America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/protest-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:52:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/protest-art/</guid>
      <description>Protest has also been a prevalent theme in art throughout the years. This timeline explores art that addresses injustice and inequality in the past 100 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufactured Consent: Five Filters of Media Bias</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/manufacturing-consent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:44:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/manufacturing-consent/</guid>
      <description>In an era of political turmoil and and misinformation, it is more important than ever to critically evaluate and critique the news media we consume. Even traditionally trustworthy news sources are not immune to bias and manipulation. Not only must we be vigilant with the accuracy of the information we consume, we must also be aware of what we’re not being told&amp;ndash;what context is being left out? What stories are being buried? What stories are being pushed? What loaded language is being used?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Black Designers You Need to Follow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/20-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:23:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/20-designers/</guid>
      <description>We all love to imagine design as the industry of the future–innovative, inclusive, progressive.  However, this field is just as prone to racial inequality as any other industry in America, if not moreso. Just check out page 14 of the 2019 AIGA Design Census. Because of this, it is imperative that we begin to recenter the conversation. White designers in the industry have an obligation to elevate our Black peers. You can start by checking out the amazing designers and organizations that I’ve listed in this Quick List for Cicada’s September newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unity of Form in Layli Long Soldier&#39;s &#39;Obligations 2&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/unity-of-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:19:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/unity-of-form/</guid>
      <description>Layli Long Soldier’s “Obligations 2” is adventurous with form. This poem confronts us with choices we must make as the reader; we can take a path through the middle, or through the edges, or a combination of both. We can read top to bottom, and we can read left to right. We can read and re-read and re-read and find a new poem each time. Whatever we do, we’re presented with the enigma of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Pandemic: The Worldwide Increase in Domestic Abuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/shadow-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:07:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/shadow-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>When global lockdowns were put into place, the world felt a little safer with the pandemic seemingly contained; however, closed doors and 24/7 confinement bred a much more sinister affliction. The UN has depicted the worldwide increase in domestic violence as a &amp;ldquo;shadow pandemic&amp;rdquo; parallel to COVID-19, saying cases of domestic abuse during the pandemic have increased by 20 percent.These numbers can only reflect the reported cases. Stress and isolation generate incendiary tensions and an absence of privacy subjects many survivors to more intimate scrutiny by their abuser, making it hard to reach out for help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Have to Say about what Marx Would Have to Say about Capitalism and COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/marx-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 19:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/marx-covid/</guid>
      <description>Where we live is a mess. It’s a convoluted, poorly meshed, dig-until-your-hands-break country. It was a rug ripped out from under those who called it home, and now it is a capitalist petri dish. It’s hard to agree on things here, even with ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding “Ching Chong House” and Anti-Asian Racism in the Wake of COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/anti-asian-racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:16:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/anti-asian-racism/</guid>
      <description>Early in July, a fake restaurant emerged on Instagram and Yelp. This fake restaurant was entitled “Ching Chong House” and had various racist menu items ranging from Corona cocktails to “Crispy Burnt Pug.” Although it is clear that this stunt is merely another in a long list of edgy shock humor, it is still worth examining given the social context we find ourselves in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reopening Schools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reopening-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:13:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/reopening-schools/</guid>
      <description>In a few weeks, millions of students will be returning to school for the fall. Despite the current COVID-19 pandemic with cases on the rise again, most schools are planning on having at least some in-person learning. For parents, this requires them to make a tough decision on whether or not to send their children to school- or to opt for online only options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Black Allyship as a Non-Black Person of Color</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/navigating-black-allyship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 19:30:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/navigating-black-allyship/</guid>
      <description>For non-Black people of color, it can be difficult to navigate allyship with the Black community, especially for those who are only just now beginning to educate themselves on Black justice. This article provides an introduction to the first steps and best practices you can take to be a better ally for Black folk in the U.S. as a non-black person of color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on allies and space on Tik Tok and Instagram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reflecting-on-allies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 19:22:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/reflecting-on-allies/</guid>
      <description>Social media has acted as a primary source of information, education, and organization throughout the Black Lives Matter movement since the its inception in 2013. It has been a platform for people to share and promote speakers, books, funds and organizations. Mass participation can create a sense of unity, community, and wide-reaching support, but done ingenuously, it can run the risk of being noise. Adding to a discussion doesn’t always mean you’re listening, and it’s easy to share recommending book lists without any intention to read them for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17 years ago: the last Brood X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/brood-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:18:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/brood-x/</guid>
      <description>The spring of 2004 raised two kinds of children. I, a proud four and a half year old, spent my time playing outside with toys and picking apart the lawn while a swath of angsty 17 year olds also emerged into the open air, ready to scream all summer long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The commodification of Black pain: Why &#39;White Fragility&#39; falls short</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/white-fragility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 19:46:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/white-fragility/</guid>
      <description>In the midst of yet another reckoning with the antiblackness that permeates every corner of the U.S., many people have scrambled for ways to make sense of it all. For some, it is a familiar topic of conversation, one that has shaped their entire life. For others, it is an abstract knowledge they may only be exploring for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cicada’s Next Step: Our New Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 18:46:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months, the world has changed in dramatic ways that have affected us all. CCM has had to contend with these changes and evolve, incorporating our original vision into a world that looks different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
