<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Issue 03: Identity on Cicada Creative Magazine</title>
    <link>/issues/issue-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Issue 03: Identity on Cicada Creative Magazine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 15:25:31 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/issues/issue-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring Is for Action</title>
      <link>/blog/spring-is-for-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:51:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spring-is-for-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration by Allyson (Alex) Lee, Creative Director&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;spring-is-for-action&#34;&gt;Spring Is For Action&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thevampdeville.com/&#34;&gt;Denise “The Vamp DeVille” Zubizarreta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; is a multi-hyphenate creative focused on interdisciplinary art making, journalism, scholarship and research. Her articles have been published with &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperallergic.com/author/denise-zubizarreta/&#34;&gt;Hyperallergic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://southwestcontemporary.com/authors/denise-the-vamp-deville-zubizarreta/&#34;&gt;Southwest Contemporary magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring is when we all come back to life after our long winter hibernation state and it’s just in time to help us recover from the daylight savings shift that nearly made it nearly impossible to defrost ourselves. It’s a time when art starts to feel sweeter and the colors engulf us in happiness and allergies. Spring also comes with the not-so-popular municipal elections which are often under-hyped in states all across the country. There’s a reason our elections take such a long break from November to April and it isn’t because of the temperature changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Denver Post even noted Denver’s tradition of holding its elections in the spring is at least a century old, probably older, according to Lucille Wenegieme, a strategic advisor for Denver Clerk and Recorder Paul López. So old, in fact, that the Denver Clerk&amp;rsquo;s office no longer has documentation on hand to pinpoint its birthday but the logic behind its inception seems to have to do with the November elections and differentiating between partisan and nonpartisan electorates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[State and federal elections held in the fall are partisan but Denver’s municipal elections are nonpartisan. In order to ease confusion for voters Denver, like many other cities, has separate voting dates to allow voters to focus on local issues instead of party politics.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many of us, voting has become a much larger topic in the last couple decades as we’ve seen drastic changes in youth voting initiatives, art covering the topic and party politics talking points, which have ranged from climate change to all out lunacy. &lt;strong&gt;Springing into action&lt;/strong&gt; this year to make our voices heard in Denver means voting for a new Mayor and this year, the options are fierce as seventeen candidates are on the ballot this time around (final votes come in on April 4th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Denver mayor is tasked with overseeing roughly 13,000 municipal workers; they also appoint hundreds of municipal leaders including the head of the airport (which is in the middle of a massive new renovation project which includes a considerable shift to the art that visitors and locals alike will experience). The mayor will set a multibillion-dollar budget, exercise veto power over City Council decisions, oversee and enforce contracts but also ensure potholes are filled, streets are swept and cops aren’t using excessive force while attempting to manage crime. It’s a powerful position and even if you’re sitting at home dealing with political fatigue from all the news clips all over the internet, this vote not only has an impact on Denver but also on Colorado’s economy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown is still suffering from the effects of the pandemic, office buildings are still empty (though I think a lot of people are happy to be remote now), restaurants have shuttered, an already raging opioid crisis has worsened, and homelessness, housing affordability, public safety and crime are all at the top of the concerns list for Denverites. This means that whatever candidate takes the vote has got a lot of work ahead of them, starting promptly on day one since they’ll inherit everything we just talked about above plus, massive expansions of downtown and Cherry Creek, arts education and funding, unionization and dissatisfaction among city workers and a plethora of other issues like our public transportation system which needs some serious work (and hopefully will pay someone better in the near future to take on the role).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I bringing all this up in an art blog, well, I’m glad you asked! Different-Level.com describes the relationship between art and politics as, &lt;strong&gt;“Multifaceted.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Art can contribute to political discourse by supporting the current political and ideological views. However, more often than not, art is a disruptive form that serves as a tool for changing existing political and social realities. Art can address certain political issues or reinterpret different social structures (for example, it can reveal different power balances in the society, offering alternative understandings of certain events, etc.)”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists can cause political change single-handedly by making the invisible - visible and by drawing attention to underrepresented political issues. I’m sure that the artists of Denver are already discussing the needs of the community while simultaneously preparing themselves for projects that take on these issues creatively, though they may still be left unresolved with a new mayor at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Springing into action this Spring isn’t just about voting, or planning out what will be in your backyard boxes this year. It&amp;rsquo;s also about being vocal in our work and how we as artists choose to share that. If you’ve also been taken over by the winter woes that have led me to hibernate quite effectively, it’s time to shake off the cobwebs, grab a brush, digital pencil, clay or whatever medium calls to you and start to get the blood flowing. The city is about to change and we’re not just talking about the strategically planted flowers that will be blooming. How will the artists of Denver take on the new world around them this season? Will they be motivated by politics or pleasure - maybe they’ll be motivated by both!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t know yet who the new mayor will be but there is no doubt that the community they will serve will remain vocal, unapologetic and vehemently passionate about sharing their concerns - in written form, on a call, through protests and even in the murals that surround them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap: What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>/blog/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roadmap-whats-next&#34;&gt;Roadmap: What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, all! It&amp;rsquo;s been a minute. We&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work here at CCM, and a few things have changed. Our Discord server got a makeover, we have the beginnings of some proper documentation, polls for Issue 07’s theme are live, and staff applications are open! But there’s lots more coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;whats-new&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s new&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;!-- Section: Timeline --&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;py-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Discord server updates&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
    We&#39;ve cleaned up the place. Between webhooks, bots, boosts, and upcoming movie nights, we think it&#39;s a pretty nice place! You can join us here with this &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/sgneFPdpNh&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.   
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Staff applications are open!&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
And will now stay open until they are filled. They are also reviewed on a rolling basis. We are currently filling Editorial Board vacancies (Web Developer, Managing Editors, Editorial Assistant, and Communications Director) and seeking Creative Team Members. Reminder! Anyone above the age of 18 can now apply. For more information, you can check the &lt;code&gt;#staff-applications&lt;/code&gt; channel on Discord or look at our &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cicadacreativemag.com/docs/staff-and-membership/&#34;&gt;documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
Speaking of which, we now have some &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cicadacreativemag.com/docs/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; for staff, prospective staff, and any curious readers. It&#39;s still under construction, but we&#39;re working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Issue 07 theme poll&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
We pitched theme concepts and voted amongst ourselves, and the top two were:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waste&lt;/strong&gt;: kitsch, hot messes, waste of time/space, decadent disgust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are here&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;: maps, wayfinding, identity
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Visit our Twitter or Instagram to vote and help break the tie. In next month&#39;s newsletter, we&#39;ll announce the winner and open submissions for Issue 07!
 &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- Section: Timeline --&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;!-- Section: Timeline --&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;py-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Announce Issue 07&#39;s theme and open submissions&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;March 2023&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        Over the next few weeks, we will let you all vote on what the theme for Issue 07 will be. At the end of the month, we will announce the winner and open submissions--reminder that submissions will now be open to anyone!
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Virtual poetry workshop&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;April 2023&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
    Introducing the long awaited virtual workshop! It will be structured similarly to review: anyone who signs up for workshop will receive a packet of peer-submitted poetry to look over. Then, we will hold a voice call where we can discuss that poetry in greater detail for the next 2 hours. Will take place on Discord.     
     &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Onboard new Creative Team members&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;May 2023&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
This will be &#34;on season&#34; for CTM, so all who are accepted will be able to attend an orientation with mock review.
     &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Close submissions and begin review&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;June 2023&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
Time to be determined. Review sessions tend to take approximately two hours. For more information on what review sessions entail, you can check the docs &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cicadacreativemag.com/docs/issue-cycles/#review&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. 
     &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;timeline-item mb-5&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;Publish Issue 07&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;fw-bold&#34;&gt;July 2023&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
    Yippee! 
     &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- Section: Timeline --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Back! Issue 06 and moving forward</title>
      <link>/blog/were-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 22:19:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/were-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;were-back-issue-06-and-moving-forward&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re Back! Issue 06 and moving forward&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director/Web Developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first&amp;ndash;go read &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../issues/issue-6/&#34;&gt;Issue 06&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;! It&amp;rsquo;s great and everyone worked really hard on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wanted to use this chance to explain our unannounced hiatus, what we learned during it, and what&amp;rsquo;s next for CCM. (Spoiler: submissions will be opening for everyone!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture this: it&amp;rsquo;s summer. We&amp;rsquo;ve finished review, finalized our selections, and drafted emails to submitters. Then, in the span of 24 hours, we lose access to our web hosting services in a messy falling out&amp;ndash;there&amp;rsquo;s barely enough time to back up our files, much less send out an announcement. Bonus: we&amp;rsquo;re told we can&amp;rsquo;t even have our domain name back for at least another month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what to do with the new time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted CCM to have a web developer&amp;ndash;a real one. I was the one who&amp;rsquo;d developed the first few iterations of our website, but I was painfully aware of my own cluelessness. I&amp;rsquo;d navigate the jungle of redundant code every issue cycle and get frustrated at how little I knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A forced month offline seemed like the perfect time to learn. I&amp;rsquo;d rebuild the website, we&amp;rsquo;d publish once we got our domain name back, and the hiccup in our timeline would be so small it&amp;rsquo;d hardly even be noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it took several months. I had so much to learn it made my head spin. I still have a lot to learn. But I feel more confident in CCM&amp;rsquo;s longevity and stability than I have since we launched, and this newfound agency has made it easier for us to do some organizational soul searching. It also enabled me to set up a blog that &lt;em&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; on Tumblr (big win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided that in the spirit of growth, we will open CCM to everyone everwhere. Issue 07 will be our first ever issue open to students and non-students alike. Staff applications will also be accessible to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;ve been other ideas floating around too&amp;ndash;special mini-zines, a monthly book club, merch, virtual workshops&amp;ndash;and we hope you&amp;rsquo;ll stick around to watch that come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for coming out again! We&amp;rsquo;re grateful for your support and patience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redecorate your Room! Find Your Inspo from 8 pieces of Interior Art</title>
      <link>/blog/redecorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 23:00:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/redecorate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;redecorate-your-room-find-your-inspo-from-8-pieces-of-interior-art&#34;&gt;Redecorate your Room! Find Your Inspo from 8 pieces of Interior Art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane Kim, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way a room is decorated can have everything to do with how you feel when you are in it. Blue painted walls might evoke feelings of tranquility and peace. For some, it might make them feel melancholy. Artists have been able to express the different types of beauty and feelings that are brought on from colors, shapes, and designs in interior design. Explore these 8 interior related art pieces to find what rooms you resonate emotionally with best, but also to gain inspiration for a new look to your room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interior (My dining room), 1909 by Wassily Kandinsky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this piece by Kandinsky, bright green and pink hues in textured oil paint vibrantly depict his perspective of his dining room. This Expressionist style emphasizes what Kandinsky felt, rather than what he directly saw in life, which ties together with the fact that he was quite fond of abstract art. Try to implement two main colors into your room, painting the door frame and walls different colors, similar to how Kandinsky has done in his piece! Incorporate textured, mixed paints to achieve a more dreamy, frenzied look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wallpaper with Blue Interior, 1992 by Roy Lichtenstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this screenprint piece, Lichtenstein’s use of bold lines, several patterns, and four bright colors stand out, making this piece fun and captivating. For room inspo, maybe you could play around with different patterns with your pillows, or walls, or add a fun, swirly rug to your floor! You could also try to choose three to four dominating colors to further demonstrate a pop-art style to your living space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/3.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interior with A Phonograph, 1924 by Henri Matisse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The warmer, sunlit tones in Matisse’s piece create a cozy home atmosphere. Like Matisse has titled in his painting, it could be nice to add a classic record player to add a touch of luxuriousness to your room. In the same way, you could invest in curtains and tapestries of different patterns and colors around the halls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/4.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Room of Flowers, 1894 by Childe Hassam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some prefer their rooms to be nice and tidy while others prefer a clutter of creativity, as seen in this piece. Similar to Matisse’s artwork, The Room of Flowers encompasses a warm, sunny feeling. You could take inspiration from this artwork by using brown, wooden tones throughout your room or add pops of color through big, blooming flowers or small, detailed trinkets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/5.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sunlit Interior from Melsted on Bornholm, 1924 by Carl Budtz-Moller&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budtz-Moller is well known for his landscape and scenery artworks that incorporate figures that tend to evoke warm feelings. Speaking in terms of room inspiration, maybe this is your sign to get a pet cat, if you don’t already have one. Furry friends make any space happier and livelier. Along with a pet cat, try matching the colors of your plants with the different objects and furniture in your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/6.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sun Shine on the Corner, 1928 by Grant Wood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This famous interior piece by Grant Wood has both a shadowy feel due to its low exposure setting and green colors. Try to make your room into a comfy greenhouse by investing in a plethora of succulents, cacti, or monsteras. Filling your space with a variety of plants is sure to make you feel more connected with the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/7.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interior (also known as Still Life, Bedroom), 1909 by Gabriele Munter. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Munter often used rich, green colors in many of her works. In this piece, Munter drew a homely setting that could be more representative of a typical home, if it were not for the very long, striped rug laid out diagonally across the room. If you feel your room feels a bit boring, add something to catch your visitors’ eyes, such as this fun piece of fabric that fills up the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/redecorate/8.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Large Studio at Castiglion, 1993 by Stephen McKenna.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen McKenna was a contemporary artist experienced in still life painting. In this piece, McKenna explored an art studio, capturing the emptiness and peacefulness of the space. As inspiration, integrate your hobby and passions into your space. It could be making your room into an art or music studio, museum, or a place to display your sticker collection over the years. Personalize your room with what you love most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tate.org.uk/art/artists/stephen-mckenna-2194&#34;&gt;https://www.tate.org.uk/art/artists/stephen-mckenna-2194&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kerlingallery.com/artists/stephen-mckenna#tab:thumbnails;tab-1:slideshow&#34;&gt;https://www.kerlingallery.com/artists/stephen-mckenna#tab:thumbnails;tab-1:slideshow&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.langmann.com/artists/carl-budtz-moller&#34;&gt;https://www.langmann.com/artists/carl-budtz-moller&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hopegallery.com/php/artist.php?artist=39&#34;&gt;https://www.hopegallery.com/php/artist.php?artist=39&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arthur.io/art/gabriele-muenter/interior-also-known-as-still-life-bedroom&#34;&gt;https://arthur.io/art/gabriele-muenter/interior-also-known-as-still-life-bedroom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/artwork/roy-lichtenstein-wallpaper-with-blue-interior&#34;&gt;https://www.artsy.net/artwork/roy-lichtenstein-wallpaper-with-blue-interior&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://germanexpressionism.net/wassily-kandinsky-german-expressionist/#:~:text=Wassily%20Kandinsky%20was%20the%20founder,the%20first%20abstract%20expressionist%20painter&#34;&gt;http://germanexpressionism.net/wassily-kandinsky-german-expressionist/#:~:text=Wassily%20Kandinsky%20was%20the%20founder,the%20first%20abstract%20expressionist%20painter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrology in Art</title>
      <link>/blog/astrology-in-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 22:52:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/astrology-in-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;astrology-in-art&#34;&gt;Astrology in Art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracie Neirynck, Publications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrology today is, I hate to say it, a bit of a joke. It makes you think of Buzzfeed and CO-Sign and while all that&amp;rsquo;s well and good, they don’t have any sizable impact on your livelihood (or at least I hope not). Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s because when we go out late at night, with a baggie hoodie draped around our shoulders and the wind is rustling through our hair and we look up at the sky, most of what we see is smog, littered with one or two sparkling stars. Our relationship with stars has drastically changed because we only ever see a handful of them at a time. Before this however, stars had a very real impact on mechanics of life and art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of ancient architecture which was inspired by stars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaco Canyon, New Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/astrology/1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temple of Sun, Machu Picchu, Peru&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/astrology/2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sun Temple, Mesa Verde, CO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/astrology/3.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/astrology/4.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​​The designs of these archaeological sites, as well as countless others are aligned with astronomical patterns in the sky above. In fact, these temples were often used for astronomical observations. Astrology has influenced the ways in which entire buildings and civilizations were constructed. When people were able to see the stars, they integrated their patterns into their daily lives. The fact that we can no longer see their patterns daily when we look up to the sky makes it far more difficult for people to align their lives with the patterns of the stars today, so what we have now in the digital age is something a little more detached from the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is sad, certainly, so many people&amp;rsquo;s attraction to astrology is kinda awesome. After all, all organic matter comes from dead stars, so our lives are intrinsically tied to them. Even if we don’t build monuments based on star placement, we still strive to be connected to them. Even with something as simple - and detached - as a horoscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/353/&#34;&gt;https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/353/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thetrekplanner.com/sun-temple-mesa-verde-national-park-colorado/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://killaexpeditions.com/winter-solstice-machu-picchu/&#34;&gt;https://killaexpeditions.com/winter-solstice-machu-picchu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thetrekplanner.com/sun-temple-mesa-verde-national-park-colorado/&#34;&gt;https://thetrekplanner.com/sun-temple-mesa-verde-national-park-colorado/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nps.gov/meve/learn/historyculture/mt_sun_temple.htm&#34;&gt;https://www.nps.gov/meve/learn/historyculture/mt_sun_temple.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Disjointed Creative Communal Isolation: The Plight of the Quarantined Creative Community</title>
      <link>/blog/communal-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 22:46:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/communal-isolation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;disjointed-creative-communal-isolation-the-plight-of-the-quarantined-creative-community&#34;&gt;Disjointed Creative Communal Isolation: The Plight of the Quarantined Creative Community&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denise  Zubizarreta, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art in isolation isn’t a new concept, many artists feel as though the isolation opens the creative mind allowing for a comprehensive connection to their work that supersedes the need for community. Edvard Munch faced a similar quarantined way of life (as we are now) in childhood. With his mother and sister dying of tuberculosis; this involuntary isolation fueled his creativity, utilizing his emotional experience (to work through his hands) in order to enhance his creative expression. Though isolation plays a significant role in the creative process, there is a much larger force that breeds ideas and motivates them into fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their research on “Deconstructing the Lone Genius Myth”, researchers Alfonso Montuori and Ronald E. Purser write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Creative expression always occurs within a cultural and historical milieu. Any discussion of creativity inevitably needs to be situated within a historical, but also sociopolitical, context. It is therefore not possible to speak of a “generic” or “universal” creativity: What is considered creative today in the United States may not have been considered creative in the same geographical area 500 years ago, and may also not be creative in China today. It is therefore important to develop an understanding of the “genealogy” of creativity and the contextual influences that led us to consider works to be creative in our present period.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They pose the most current question and concern, how has creativity in today’s market changed the way creatives develop their crafts? With the meaning of “community” feeling loose in today&amp;rsquo;s world, social media sites like Facebook and Instagram have fostered a disjoined communal creative isolation that has become the norm. Breeding the isolation so many are perplexed by today. Gone are the days of Munch, isolated truly, with few tasks to choose from in order to fight the burdening boredom. The world may see a shift in their communities but artists have been flourishing behind these scenes, as technology has connected even the most agoraphobic of creative minds. Those who seek the connection of the outside world are finding themselves consumed by the complexities of their most inner circle, home. Breading a need for creative expression but void of the universe&amp;rsquo;s tangible vastness, only to cling to (what may be seen as) the mundane. British artist Gareth Fuller is exploring the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Each day for two weeks, Fuller depicted his experiences and thoughts from inside his 590 square foot apartment. The result is a series of 14 drawings titled “The Quarantine Maps.” …By day 9, Fuller finds himself thinking beyond the parameters of what he could see. The series becomes less about the artist&amp;rsquo;s personal triumphs and more about capturing the experiences of those who are just beginning to make sense of the crisis.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other artists like Ray Materson found purpose in isolation, a way to ease the mind and find control in the uncontrollable. Teaching himself to embroider in prison, his threads of unraveled socks depict not only the internal processing of his drug addiction, but the imagination of a life outside of his shackled existence. What does this mean for the current masses and their exploration of self in the continual pursuit of healthy coping mechanisms (that were difficult to find already)? The artistic community has not only connected but it has cultivated an online presence that keeps the modern artist feeling unified during the most uncertain of times; with an ever-streaming flow of validation that their existence is not futile. The artist’s plight is to allow the sense of community to be as pliable as their imagination and somehow harnessing that peace in the most unimaginable of paroxysms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some choose to create based on the isolation itself. Others find solace in the connectivity we’ve fostered through an online experience, that is only being fortified more intensely as we continue to socially distance our energies. The artist finds itself now consumed with how to plug-in to the intensity of the masses. Striving to unify the world through visuals that connect us, although we find ourselves strategically isolated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of the artist remains the same today as it was yesterday when they had their “freedom of social distance” - the change here and call to action is the artist coming to the realization that “community” can be regarded for its boundlessness. Distance truly matters not, with our cultivation of modern technology. What matters now is how we cultivate the essence of that disconnection, interpret it and showcase it to the world; not only for our own sanity but for the collective exhale of a society at large, in desperation for a full-bodied organic transmission in an overwhelmingly digital existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bibliography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christensen, Tanner. “The Role Isolation Plays in the Creative Process.” Creative Something. Last modified December 10, 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativesomething.net/post/2018/12/9/the-role-isolation-plays-in-creativity&#34;&gt;https://creativesomething.net/post/2018/12/9/the-role-isolation-plays-in-creativity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Di Liscia, Valentina. “The Artists Who Found Inspiration In Isolation.” Hyperallergic. Last modified March 20, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperallergic.com/548698/artists-isolation/&#34;&gt;https://hyperallergic.com/548698/artists-isolation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Montuori, Alfonso and Ronald Purser. Deconstructing the Lone Genius Myth: Toward a Contextual View of Creativity. Journal of Humanistic Psychology - J HUM PSYCHOL., 1995. 71.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stewart, Jessica. “8 Startling Facts About the Troubled Life of Edvard Munch.” My Modern Met. Last modified March 12, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mymodernmet.com/edvard-munch-facts/&#34;&gt;https://mymodernmet.com/edvard-munch-facts/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsui, Karina. “What Happens When a Map Artist Goes Into Quarantine.” CNN, Style. Last modified March, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/style/article/gareth-fuller-maps-coronavirus-quarantine/index.html&#34;&gt;https://www.cnn.com/style/article/gareth-fuller-maps-coronavirus-quarantine/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gothic Influence in Horror Art</title>
      <link>/blog/gothic-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 22:32:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gothic-horror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;gothic-influence-in-horror-art&#34;&gt;Gothic Influence in Horror Art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracie Neirynck, Publications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothic art may make you think of poorly painted Medieval friezes, but this spooky season, let’s think about another form of Gothic art. Art inspired by the themes of Gothic fiction, also known as Gothic Horror. Read more to see the work of 6 talented artists who evoke the Gothic themes of sadness, fear, and terror in their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Enrico Robusti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Italian painter, Enrico Rbusti 
completed a degree in Law before starting a career in the arts. Although
the paintings don’t have typical gothic elements, I think there&amp;rsquo;s 
something wonderfully horrifying about his style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/1.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/2.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Lukasz Banach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known better under his pseudonym Norman Leto, Lukasz Banach was born in Poland and was a self-taught artist interested in both painting and video production. He became friends with Zdzislaw Bekinski (a painter towards the bottom of this list), who influenced his form and style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/3.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/4.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/5.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/thirios&#34;&gt;Anastasios Gionis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anastasios Gionis is a character modeler and texture artist who creates different monster concepts for tv and video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/6.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/7.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Valerie Patterson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie Patterson uses primarily watercolor to enliven her paintings. Although her paintings are much more psychedelic than gothic, her works still have an eerie feel to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/8.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/9.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/10.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Eric Lacombe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another self-taught artist, Eric Lacombe is both a digital artist and painter who uses mixed media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/11.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/12.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Zdzisław Beksiński&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite on this list, Zdzisław Beksiński was a Polish artist. Although his paintings display gothic and utopian elements, Beksiński was recorded as being a positive and pleasant man who refused to analyze his own paintings or attribute one sole meaning onto them. Zdzisław Beksiński was stabbed to death in 2005 by a 19-year-old presumably because he refused to lend the boy 100 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/13.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/14.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/gothic/15.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Guess We’ll Never Know: Ambiguous Endings in Horror</title>
      <link>/blog/ambiguous-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:28:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ambiguous-endings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-guess-well-never-know-ambiguous-endings-in-horror&#34;&gt;I Guess We’ll Never Know: Ambiguous Endings in Horror&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Dunn, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best horror movies have ambiguous endings. Endings that make you leave confused, in disbelief, and searching the internet for more details and answers. The movie remains in your head, and you’re stuck thinking, what happens next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambiguous endings are the opposite of catharsis. Where you expect a release of tension, you instead get confusion and a desire to know more. But this is the ideal outcome of horror, which wants you at the edge of your seat the whole team, and often is focused on thematic notions rather than technical plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example is &lt;em&gt;El hoyo&lt;/em&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;The Platform&lt;/em&gt;) a Spanish film that debuted on Netflix in March 2020. &lt;em&gt;El hoyo&lt;/em&gt;  takes place in a fictional society in which hundreds of people are kept together, two to a floor, in a massive tower. Each floor is a single room with a hole in the middle, which a flat platform full of food passes through once a day. Each floor gets several minutes to eat what they can before the platform descends to the next floor. The platform was designed to have just enough food for every inmate, but that design implies that those on the top floor, with first access to the food, will only take what they need. Of course, as anyone below floor 50 learns, no one acts with the whole in mind. Hunger takes over, and those at the button turn to each other to feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The themes of gluttony and selfishness, catalyzed by privilege, were especially impactful in March 2020, when many Americans refused to socially distance in favor of routine, normalcy, partying and the abstract notion of American freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without totally revealing the ending (go watch it for yourself, especially if you were a fan of Squid Game), &lt;em&gt;El hoyo&lt;/em&gt; ends with a single, blurry shot of a character about to leave the tower, but with no actual exit. There is no Hunger Games-style triumphant overhaul of the unjust institution. There is not even much consideration of the architects of the tower. The ending is abrupt and unclear, leaving the viewer with only a blurry, rapid-paced final shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A far more famous horror movie, &lt;em&gt;The Thing&lt;/em&gt;, used ambiguity to create impact,  as well. In &lt;em&gt;The Thing&lt;/em&gt;, it is never confirmed that the alien creature is  killed, and the viewer is left just as paranoid and suspicious as the  main cast was throughout the majority of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Shining&lt;/em&gt;, ambiguity is used to twist the ending. It reveals that the main character, Jack Torrance, can be spotted in a photograph from the 1920s. That revelation is not followed by any additional details, and the viewer has to consider all the hints throughout the movie of what that could possibly mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of ending is my favorite in all kinds of movies, but especially in horror. Without a clear resolution, the tension that has been built up throughout the whole movie seems to carry, and it’s not until the credits roll in that the viewer realizes they can breathe again. The catharsis comes from realizing that you are free from the stress of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ambiguous ending also focuses the final few moments on the film on the emotional or philosophical themes of the film. Injustice, paranoia, madness. In &lt;em&gt;El Hoyo&lt;/em&gt;, the ending leaves the story figuratively contained within the levels of the tower. The  focus is not on the unfair institution, but the impact that has on the  people trapped within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calming release of catharsis is unnecessary in horror; you want to leave the theater feeling rattled and even confused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Healthy Escapism</title>
      <link>/blog/escapism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:06:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/escapism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-healthy-escapism&#34;&gt;On Healthy Escapism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Escapism gets a bad rap, understandably so. It’s often perceived as someone running away from their feelings by refusing to engage with reality&amp;ndash;an unhealthy coping mechanism. Conventional wisdom says that the Right Way™ to deal with negative emotions is to feel all of it and work through the weeds of it. Maybe you talk it out with friends, have a good cry, or draw a bubble bath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried all that. It makes me feel worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember my life in media phases&amp;ndash;kindergarten was Yu Yu Hakusho, 5th grade was Linkin Park. 10th grade was Agatha Christie. 12th was Terraria. Media interests serve as time capsules for me; escapism has always been my most useful coping tool. When times get especially difficult and I’m too overwhelmed, I don’t want a goddamn bubble bath or to talk about it. I want to shut my brain off and rewatch anime I liked as a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, what happens is that once my stress comes down, I can actually examine my feelings without imploding. I’ve regulated myself back to a baseline. I need to calm down to get perspective, and one way to achieve that is to be distracted by a story that has nothing to do with the here-and-now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won’t pretend it hasn’t ever been dysfunctional. I find it’s extraordinarily effective&amp;ndash;perhaps too effective. All coping strategies must be tempered. Too much of a good thing is a bad thing. Ground rules must be set. These are my personal guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set aside specific amounts of time. Schedule your escapism. For some people, this looks like playing half an hour of their favorite video game every day. For some, it means blocking out a whole day to get all their escapism in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose media that will regulate you. If you’re immersing yourself in media that you used to like, but now reminds you of your mean high school friend and creepy boss at McDonalds, it probably won’t comfort you much. It’ll get your mind off the here and now, but do you really want to go there?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t feel guilty. As long as your responsibilities aren’t shirked and you’re in one piece, you’re doing fine. Too often, we’re made to feel guilty for not being productive. But you don’t have to be productive. You don’t have to  justify your existence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you process your feelings best by sitting quietly and thinking about them, fantastic. If talking it out with your friends and being surrounded by people makes you feel better, great. But if you’re like me and you know that letting yourself fall apart will do more harm than good, don’t feel bad about needing a few hours to get away from everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margin Doodles of a Monster Named Stress</title>
      <link>/blog/margin-doodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 21:06:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/margin-doodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;margin-doodles-of-a-monster-named-stress&#34;&gt;Margin Doodles of a Monster Named Stress&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracie Neirynck, Publications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes stress can take hold of you, reaching its withering hands around your body, plucking at your heartstrings like it’s playing guitar. If you’re like me (unprepared and disorganized), then the beginning of the school year can be particularly stressful. The stress monster can linger at the corner of your eyes, fading into a haze when you try to look at it head on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve done my best to confront that stress, and hopefully explain what happens to you when you get stressed. When you experience stress, the amygdala, the emotional center of your brain, sends signals to the hippocampus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/stress/stress1.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hippocampus, which regulates memory, then sends signals to the rest of the nervous system, sending your system into a state of flight or fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/stress/stress2.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can increase your heart rate and heighten your senses, and prompts the release of cortisol, a hormone related to your stress response. Stressful events send us into a state of preparing for danger which isn’t necessarily there, and while stress can be healthy in moderation, it is important to recognize the effects it has on our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/stress/stress3.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fill! Your! Pages!</title>
      <link>/blog/fill-your-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 22:19:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fill-your-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fill-your-pages&#34;&gt;Fill! Your! Pages!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peyton Farnum, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finishing something you worked really hard on might just be one of the best feelings in the world. But what makes this accomplishment feel even more fulfilling? When you planned every step of the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an artist with a constant myriad of ideas for projects, carrying out said projects can be more chaotic and disorganized than necessary. I found that sometimes the process of one piece would be mixed up with the potential ideas for another, which made it difficult for me to stay focused. Luckily, I find solace in utilizing the empty pages of my sketchbook and my desire for aesthetic organization. To create more clarity, I started designing pages dedicated to sorting out my ideas for all of my projects. These helped me keep track of the goals I had for my work, such as subject, messages/themes, inspirations and stylistic choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/pages/1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/pages/2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two of my pieces and their planning pages from a past portfolio about endangered species of wildlife. I began with choosing the animals I wanted to focus on and researching them. (Sometimes these choices came with inspiration from other media, such as books!) For these pieces, I chose the Chinese pangolin and the okapi. I completed studies of their forms and colors in the wild and assessed how I wanted to convey them in my work, leading up to thumbnails and design ideas for the final. Alongside these studies came aesthetic and technical decisions such as color schemes and mediums. In my pangolin piece sketches, I noticed that the pangolins&amp;rsquo; rigid scales fit together like a puzzle, allowing me to visualize a piece that focused less on depth and more on positive and negative shapes. I decided to try out printmaking to best convey the species stylistically and along came a design that resembled a maze around the animal. This was a great experiment for me and I fell in love with printmaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/pages/3.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/pages/4.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my okapi piece, I worked from a base idea of a scene in Barbara Kingsolver’s &lt;em&gt;The Poisonwood Bible&lt;/em&gt; in which one of the characters meets an okapi in a jungle. The scene is treated as a sacred and mysterious moment that I felt captured the alluring nature of the okapi&amp;ndash;it quickly became one of my favorite scenes in the story. While making my planning page, I decided to take it a step further in my own ideas and create the appearance of an okapi that was more grand and fictional to add to the mythicality of the work. I realized with the dense jungle background that I would need a medium that would be good to layer with. That’s how I arrived at my watercolor conclusion, which was further solidified after I did some color swatches with them on my planning page. The myriad of blues and greens really caught my eye and I ended up using them in the final. Needless to say, having a few pages to just jot or doodle down ideas led me down so many avenues of possibility! I don’t think my completed pieces would have developed to their full potential without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I won’t discredit the excitement that spontaneity brings, I will admit that these planning pages have helped me immensely as an artist. Some of my most successful pieces began with me jotting down simple ideas, followed by filling the page around them and watching them grow into the final projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning doesn’t have to be monotonous or boring, it is only meant to help you! Make it a fun part of the project. Decorate with color, doodles, collage elements, medium experiments, subjects studies, literally anything! Just discover your own method of creating organized chaos and fill your pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; no matter what kind of creative you are, you may benefit from filling your lists or sketchbook pages as much as you can. Write/draw/make note of everything that comes to your head. You never know what may inspire you or take your projects to the next level of amazingness and originality!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Cicada are you?</title>
      <link>/blog/cicada-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 22:12:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cicada-quiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;which-cicada-are-you&#34;&gt;Which Cicada are you?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made for fun! Brought to you by Cicada Creative Magazine. CW // photos of bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uquiz.com/quiz/xIPn5U/which-cicada-are-you&#34;&gt;Take the quiz here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is art boundary-breaking if it’s stolen?</title>
      <link>/blog/boundary-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 22:07:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/boundary-breaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-art-boundary-breaking-if-its-stolen&#34;&gt;Is art boundary-breaking if it’s stolen?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Dunn, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re back in high school, working on a group project with the artsy philosophy guy who exclusively talks back to his female teachers. The project requires you to bring in some sort of family heirloom from home to share with your partner and then present to the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you brought in a book that is significant to your parents. When it’s time to present the book to class, the philosophy guy grabs the book out of your hands and decides presents for you. He had obviously not listened to anything you said about the book’s plot and sentimental meaning, and instead spends ten minutes describing how the cover art challenges the oppressive art norms set by society. The class initially laughs, but years later you see the same guy on the cover of a magazine being celebrated for his unique, groundbreaking art style. It’s a blatant copy of the cover of your family’s book. The book which he barely cared to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m getting at is that Pablo Picasso is the artsy philosophy guy. He’s also sexist and colonialist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demoiselles d’Avignon was Pablo Picasso’s groundbreaking piece that drew ire from art traditionalists and respect and love from modern day art historians. The piece became famous for its explicit depiction of female nudity, which was “unflinching” and unfeminine. It was also one of the benchmark examples of Picasso’s developing cubist style, and displayed the women with flattened, misshapen faces and bodies. Two of the women’s faces are so distorted that they resemble masks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was well known that Picasso admired African masks and referenced the collection of masks he owned while painting Demoiselles. “African masks” as it is used here functions as a catch-all term, as Picasso considered all the cultures of the continent as one homogenous art form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picasso admired African art not because he understood it’s history, purpose and intent, but because, to him, it represented a civilization untainted by industrialization and development. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/3045764&#34;&gt;art historian Patricia Leighte&lt;/a&gt;, Picasso saw this condensed African culture as a primitive, authentic, simple one that served as a refreshing escape from the “decadent” West. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picasso saw these masks as inspiration objects that guided him on his path of abstraction and eventually cubism. When recounting a trip to a museum, &lt;a href=&#34;https://christopherpjones.medium.com/picasso-primitivism-and-the-rights-and-wrongs-of-cultural-appropriation-1f964fa61cee&#34;&gt;he described&lt;/a&gt; the wonder he felt when studying a mask originating from Sub-Saharan Africa. “These objects [were] created with a sacred, magical purpose, to serve as intermediaries between [the artist’s people] and the unknown, hostile forces surrounding them, attempting in that way to overcome their fears by giving them color and form.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picasso thought he was coming from a good place, and that by “celebrating” what he called “primitivism,” he was acting against colonial forces. However, his philosophy came from a place of egoism and psycho-social colonialism. He thought that African people were, by natural, “primitive” and unburdened by invention. He interpreted the African masks with no research into their history or origin. (Even if he wished to, how could he? They were stolen from Africa by French colonizers.) Rather than learning more about the art’s original context, Picasso injected his own that was based off of stereotypical and reductive assumptions of an entire continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa is a diverse continent full of thousands of ethnic groups and tribes that have been divided across European-imposed geographic lines into 54 countries. African art should not be boiled down, misconstrued and taken as an aesthetic or ideology for Western artists to play with. It belittles the wide variation of cultures, the complexity of its people and the depth of it’s art. Belittling all of one continent’s culture is what &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undertheplumblossomtree.com/2015/07/picasso-and-primitivism-story-behind.html&#34;&gt;justified colonialism &lt;/a&gt;for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if the Western world had been introduced to African art through the people rather than by theft. What kind of art would come from a respectful cultural exchange between European painters and African performers and mask-makers? What if Western painters could witness the Baule peoples’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/312340&#34;&gt;portrait masks&lt;/a&gt; in action during a performance? Or learn about the way that the Chokwe people celebrate and honor mothers and women through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artic.edu/artworks/120215/female-face-mask-mwana-pwo&#34;&gt;masks&lt;/a&gt; and performance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As art historians recognize Pablo Picasso’s influence on the art world, they should pay equal attention to the African artists whose art is inspired by the same source material, but on a much deeper and empathetic level. Francis Nnaggenda, a Ugandan artist, is often compared to Picasso. His &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gobronze.org/artists/langland/baana.html&#34;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt;? “People tell me my work looks like Picasso, but they have it wrong. It is Picasso who looks like me, like Africa.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That time Andy Warhol plagiarized Yayoi Kusama</title>
      <link>/blog/warhol-kusama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 22:03:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/warhol-kusama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;that-time-andy-warhol-plagiarized-yayoi-kusama&#34;&gt;That time Andy Warhol plagiarized Yayoi Kusama&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you asked a stranger to list any 5 artists off the top of their head, odds are good that Andy Warhol would be one of them. A soup can homage even sits in front of CSU’s Center for the Arts (to honor a visit from Warhol in 1981). There is no doubt that his contributions altered the trajectory of American art. He also copied part of one of Yayoi Kusama’s exhibitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yayoi Kusama is another famous artist, albeit less of a household name than Warhol. She’s a Japanese artist who immigrated to New York in 1958 and she helped carve out the pop art scene of the 60s. As a child, she suffered from hallucinations and trauma, something that she has spent her entire career exploring through art. Her work is extremely personal to her&amp;ndash;she has been open about this since her arrival to the art scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kusama’s very first solo exhibition, “Aggregation: One Thousands Boats Show,” showcased a rowboat sculpture made of phallic shapes, complete with two similarly adorned oars. The structure was photographed then replicated 999 times on the walls and ceilings. Warhol visited the exhibit and complimented Kusama on it, specifically commenting on the wallpaper and floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/kusama1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, Warhol would debut his “Cow Wallpaper” installation in his April 1966 exhibition at Leo Castelli Gallery, featuring one of his most recognizable and famous designs. The similarity wasn’t lost on the art community. The Museum of Modern Art even mentions it in their interactive display about Kusama’s show, remarking that Kusama’s exhibit appeared 3 years before Warhol’s. However, Warhol credited an art dealer for the idea and did not mention Kusama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/warhol1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years later, Warhol would debut his “Cow Wallpaper” installation in his April 1966 exhibition at Leo Castelli Gallery, featuring one of his most recognizable and famous designs. The similarity wasn’t lost on the art community. The Museum of Modern Art &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moma.org/interactives/exhibitions/1998/kusama/manual/text_10.html&#34;&gt;even mentions it&lt;/a&gt; in their interactive display about Kusama’s show, remarking that Kusama’s exhibit appeared 3 years before Warhol’s. However, Warhol credited an art dealer for the idea and did not mention Kusama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kusama would go on to have more ideas stolen from her by her peers, namely Claes Oldenberg and Lucas Samaras. When Kusama visited Claes Oldenberg’s exhibit and saw he’d taken her idea of soft sculpture, his wife approached her and apologized. Then, Kusama watched these ideas&amp;ndash;her ideas&amp;ndash;manifest in wealth and success that she could not herself achieve. She became paranoid and isolated herself, hiding her art. Her mental health deteriorated. This culminated in a suicide attempt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bout of depressive episodes compounded by the rejection she faced upon returning to Japan, she checked herself into a mental health facility and has not checked out since. She still makes intimate art that addresses her trauma, psychosis, and other aspects of her life. She still says art saved her life. She is one of the most famous contemporary artists and her work has affected millions. But it took much longer for her to ascend to these heights than her white male peers who copied her ideas and we must examine why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line for plagiarism can be blurry; originality is harder to define in creative contexts. Some artists flirt with this line and some brazenly cross it. Yayaoi Kusama’s story demonstrates why even “minor” plagiarism is so insidious, even in ways that the plagiarizer may not have been aware of. These artists “drew inspiration” from her work and got fame and acclaim while she struggled to eat. The reason as to why it was easier for these men to achieve fame is clear: the art scene was heavily male dominated and almost entirely white. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the anti-Asian racism in the USA is at a fever pitch. Hate crimes have been on the rise since COVID-19 first began to spread in the USA, something many (including former President Trump) attributed to China, dubbing it “China virus.” I touched on this uptick in violence against Asians in 2020 on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cicadacreativemag.com/post/627081264345841664/titlename-position-preview&#34;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt;, but it has only gotten worse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, 8 women were murdered in Atlanta on March 16, 6 of them Asian. I don’t want to derail the primary topic of this post and this event warrants a post all on its own, but it has become clearer and clearer that Asian women are not valued as much as their white counterparts, especially when those counterparts are men. This is true for all Asian people living in the USA. The pattern of devaluing the work of women of color is one that we can address within our own communities&amp;ndash;racism and misogyny are systemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, maybe we could let go of Andy Warhol a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20180925-yayoi-kusamas-extraordinary-survival-story&#34;&gt;https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20180925-yayoi-kusamas-extraordinary-survival-story&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moma.org/interactives/exhibitions/1998/kusama/kusama_11.html&#34;&gt;https://www.moma.org/interactives/exhibitions/1998/kusama/kusama_11.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artspace.com/magazine/art_101/close_look/pop-art-ripoffs-the-3-yayoi-kusama-artworks-that-warhol-oldenburg-and-samaras-copied-in-the-60s-55636&#34;&gt;https://www.artspace.com/magazine/art_101/close_look/pop-art-ripoffs-the-3-yayoi-kusama-artworks-that-warhol-oldenburg-and-samaras-copied-in-the-60s-55636&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/16/us/atlanta-shootings-massage-parlor.html&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/16/us/atlanta-shootings-massage-parlor.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in punk!</title>
      <link>/blog/punk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 21:59:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/punk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;women-in-punk&#34;&gt;Women in punk!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molly Flood, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Punk Movement was largely male-dominated, as much of the music industry is, but the women of Punk embodied the movement wholly and didn&amp;rsquo;t receive adequate credit. The movement’s female artists highlighted the struggles of the female experience that didn&amp;rsquo;t fit into the mainstream narrative. In their focus on anger and style of dressing, the women of the Punk Movement pushed back against societal norms more effectively than the more popular male bands could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/punk1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thefix.com/joan-jetts-bad-reputation&#34;&gt;https://www.thefix.com/joan-jetts-bad-reputation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anger and passionate unhinged expression were central to the Punk Movement and many of its subgenres. Punk women dominated in honing their anger through violent performances and shouting in sets. Seeing a male artist yelling on stage didn&amp;rsquo;t bring the shock factor they thought it did. Angry men yelling about their problems has always been accepted by society and even encouraged. While the men yelled, Joan Jett and many other women in the Punk Movement yelled back, with iconic performances such as Jett’s “Bad Reputation”.  Performances like this brought a sense of empowerment to the female experience and anger like never before and gave voice to the frustration marginalized groups had been and will continue to feel for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else did the women of the Punk Movement do exceptionally well? Style. Patti Smith embodied a hands-off effortless androgynous style rarely done at the time. With a short, shag-style haircut, oversized men’s clothes, and a bare face, Smith’s unique style pushed back on the patriarchy’s notions of how women in the spotlight had to dress to be accepted or well-liked. Smith&amp;rsquo;s style perpetuated the punk movement theme of dismantling gendered clothing but personalized to her own gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/punk2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/shemp65/5397827655&#34;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/shemp65/5397827655&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women in Punk made a mark on the path of alternative rock that has forever shifted the trajectory of non-male artists in the genre. To honor women in March is to not look just at women in power today or the most famous figures in women’s history, but it is to take a step back and realize how much of your personal influence and inspiration wouldn’t be the same without the more niche contributions of women throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Love Story</title>
      <link>/blog/love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:57:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/love-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-love-story&#34;&gt;A Love Story&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracie Neirynck, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agh, February! The month of love. This month I was determined to present you all with a love story—cliché, I know. In my desperate quest for a love story, I scanned the internet, spending many hours skimming across its many whimsical love poems and falling victim to its endless rabbit holes. I even braved the journey into the desperate and truly dangerous land of the second page of Google (yes, turns out it does exist), determined to find the perfect love story. After many (oh so many) futile hours of reading about the many people littered across history who died for each other, killed for each other, wrote for each other, loved each other, this is the only love story I want to tell you all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to set the scene: it is early in the morning, a tired 5 a.m. This is not the fun 5 a.m. It&amp;rsquo;s not Saturday at 5 a.m. at the drive-through at Taco Bell coming back from a road trip. This is not the drunken 5 a.m., sitting on the kitchen floor with your friends waiting for the microwave to cook an entire bag of pizza rolls. You are not in an airplane looking out the window over to the lights in the city, wondering who is still awake. You have not woken up to begin that steep climb up the mountain, racing the sunrise to the top. No, this 5 a.m. is different. The hour where you feel like someone has taken your brain and rung it out like a washcloth, where your bones have turned to molasses under your skin and you are pretty sure that you are incapable of walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We open here, on an October 5 a.m. where my mother has just been woken up by contractions as she realizes that her first child is on the way. You can imagine the chaos that follows, the half-asleep rush to the hospital, and the many hours of labor. As my mom enters labor, she receives an epidural to numb the pain. While epidurals numb the pain of labor, they can also prolong it. This is what happens to my mom, who endures nearly 23 hours of labor before my sister is born. When midnight rolls around, everyone has fallen asleep as my mom is still not yet in active labor. My dad is passed out in the chair next to the hospital bed, but my mom refuses to go to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an EKG hooked up to my mom&amp;rsquo;s belly, recording my sister&amp;rsquo;s heartbeat, making sure that my sister stays alive throughout the night. If my sister&amp;rsquo;s heart were to stop beating at some point during, the nurses and doctors would be alerted. Unfortunately, my mom doesn’t know this. So, my mom, who has been in labor for nineteen hours at this point, forces herself to stay awake for the entire night, watching the rhythm of my sister’s heartbeat on the screen. Fighting off the sandman with grit, she stays up the whole night, her eyes glued to EKG, making sure that my sister’s heart keeps beating throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She recounts this as stupid now, rolls her eyes and laughs at herself. She says she should have just gone to sleep, but she didn’t. So, there you have it: maybe a little atypical, but it&amp;rsquo;s what comes to my mind when someone asks me to tell them a love story. We often think that romantic love stories are the ones worth telling, the grand gestures and dramatic speeches. However, most love stories to me aren’t romantic; they are quiet and humble and are easily mistaken for the dust and monotony of everyday life, and these are my favorite kinds of love stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Swamp Inspired Me</title>
      <link>/blog/swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:51:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/swamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-the-swamp-inspired-me&#34;&gt;How the Swamp Inspired Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peyton Farnum, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love wildlife. I have ever since I was a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up as a young girl living near the swamps of Savannah, Georgia. My dad and I would go for walks in the lush green forests that met with the wetlands of the coast. The nutria would swim down the bayous, making wakes with their tail as I watched them, crouched by the water’s edge. Tall cattail plants that seemed to reach as high as the sky would block my view until dad lifted me up onto his shoulders. The frogs would croak and form a rhythmic chorus that allowed the swamp to echo with life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dad would point at birds that swooped by and tell me the names of each species he recognized, encouraging me to mimic their calls alongside him. I’d look with awe and ponder how the swamp came to be so breathtaking. The wildlife of Savannah became my home, my childhood, and fostered my love for nature. Eventually, I grew taller than the cattails on the water’s edge, and circumstances led my family away from the swamps of Savannah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this time, the swamp stuck with me. I remember the fondness I felt for the wildlife back then, and as I have grown, this fondness has found a home with another passion of mine: my love for art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad, in our downtime away from the swamp, would hand me paint brushes or pencils and let me create whatever I wanted. The world became my blank canvas in these moments. I realized that creating was something so freeing, so sincere, so magical. Since then, I have held onto the feelings that those memories have given me: the intensity of discovering what I love so dearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within these passions I have found happiness in combining these two parts of my identity. I incorporate animals and nature into my art at every opportunity possible, spending countless hours observing animals I see or read about. Every time I am struck with new inspiration, I fall in love with art and wildlife all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a college freshman, these passions still hold a special place in my heart, and I am certain that they are not going anywhere any time soon. Recently, I completed a portfolio project that focused entirely on endangered species, such as the pangolin, okapi, and Amur leopard. This project was not only intended to showcase my love for these animal subjects, but also to call attention to species that are in need in our world. It was one of my favorite projects of my artistic career so far, as I felt the message behind them was meaningful to a cause I feel strongly for. I think back to my younger self and I know that past me would be proud of all I have created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love wildlife, and I love art, and I owe it all to the inspiration that the swamp gave to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/swamp.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Tattoo Artists That Make Me Want to Cover My Skin in Ink</title>
      <link>/blog/tattoo-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:43:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tattoo-artists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;top-10-tattoo-artists-that-make-me-want-to-cover-my-skin-in-ink&#34;&gt;Top 10 Tattoo Artists That Make Me Want to Cover My Skin in Ink&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peyton Farnum, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my many years as a creative-driven being, I’ve discovered that I have a great affinity for tattoo art. Tattoo practice is something that is taboo in our society because of its permanence. However, tattoo artists are just as credible as other artists, and their art is worthy of admiration and respect! Especially because there is much effort and tireless work that goes into being a professional tattoo artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to express my love for the world of tattoo art, I have compiled a list of my favorite skin-ink artists I found throughout the years. These artists come from all over the world and have phenomenal and unique styles. Just admiring these artists through social media fuels my desire to cover my whole body in beautiful artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(All of the artists on this list can be found on Instagram)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;m_tendo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/1.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M_tendo displays stunning technique across many styles, including realism and abstraction. Their technique in using single needles for realistic pieces make for beautifully detailed end products that I could look at for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zzizziboy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/2.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zzizziboy’s graphic style has a special place in my heart. Their designs are simplistic, yet fun, featuring beautifully vibrant colors. In addition, all their work is handpoked, showcasing a fascinating tattooing technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anka.tattoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/3.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anka.tattoo’s displays incredible artistry in all of their drawings and tattoos. Their style walks a beautiful line between stylized and realistic. Not to mention their phenomenal technical linework and hatch shading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xoxotattoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/4.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xoxotattoo’s work caught my eye because of their delicate linework. Most of their designs are completed with a single needle and intricate craftsmanship. You can obverse all the meticulous details in every one of their tattoos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;takemymuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/5.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takemymuse’s work is always a delight to see. Their designs are often simple linework combined with colored detailing, often in pastel color palettes. From animals to portraits, their tattoos always bring a fond emotion and a smile to my face because of their playful nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;julianllouve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/6.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julianllouve’s work displays interest and chaos in every piece. Their bright colors and crazy energies are nothing short of the epitome of psychedelic. I feel like I am looking at a museum-worthy surrealist work whenever I see their tattoos in my feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anniemesstattoos-blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/7.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anniemesstattoos has an incredible way of depicting figures in tattoos. Her linework is well crafted yet whimsical and beautiful. Many of her recent subjects focus on stylized depictions of women characters such as the Greek goddess Athena (pictured).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pitta_kkm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/8.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitta_kkm is a master of East Asian style in tattoos. Their pieces often include those of Korean legends such as dragons or stylized Korean clouds. Their tattoos are usually large, spanning whole sleeves, filled with vibrant colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bowsertattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/9.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowsertattoos pieces display a style that is both childlike and seemingly unsettling. Their works often feature black lined subjects that lack shading and depth. Their designs are simplistic yet haphazardous, that always leave me curious of the meaning behind the tattoo (if there is one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;88world.co.kr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/tattoos/10.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88world.co.kr has shown incredible success with pixelated style tattoos. Their pieces appear beautifully bold and rich in color, tied together by meticulous handiwork with each individual square pixel. They do a marvelous job of displaying clean lines on the surface of skin, which exists without a pixelated grid guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring ugly babies across art history</title>
      <link>/blog/ugly-babies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 21:16:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ugly-babies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;scoring-ugly-babies-across-art-history&#34;&gt;Scoring ugly babies across art history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Dunn, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone visiting an art museum or studying art history has probably encountered a weirdly shaped baby at some point in their life. These long-limbed babies, resembling a small man or wrinkly sock puppet, are a common staple of art from the Middle Ages all the way up into the Renaissance. It seems that no matter the style or medium, European artists could never quite get babies right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These weirdly rendered babies were inspired by the concept of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2015/7/8/8908825/ugly-medieval-babies&#34;&gt;“homunculus,” meaning little man&lt;/a&gt;. Depictions of one baby in particular, the infant Jesus, was especially prone to be depicted as a little man because it suggested he was born as a perfectly formed man rather than as a inadequate chubby baby. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to determine the most cursed baby, I’ll be grading them on a three-part scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proportions:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the baby like a tiny little man? Or does it, disappointingly, look like an actual baby. We’re going for the most cursed proportions here for five stars. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attitude:&lt;/strong&gt; Does this baby look upset? Serious? Or curious, like an actual baby? The more theatrical of an expression or pose, the more attitude stars this cursed baby gets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Style:&lt;/strong&gt; Does this baby have a unique flair that only this baby can pull off? Does it radiate &lt;em&gt;je ne sais quoi&lt;/em&gt;? We’re looking for star quality here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;235&#34;&gt;2.3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/1.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/436245&#34;&gt;Albrecht Dürer, Virgin and Child. 1516.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 0/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 2/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This baby looks very normal. He’s chubby, proportioned well, but he’s got the expression of someone who just overhead someone else diss him from across the room. His alertness is a little unsettling. Final score: 2.3/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;35&#34;&gt;3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/2.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/336208&#34;&gt;Hans Wechtlin, Virgin and Child. ca. 1510.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 2/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 4/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This baby features an exceptional page boy cut that suits his scholarly demeanor. I’m sure he could be more cursed, but I’d surely never like to see this sort of child in a library. Final score: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;35-1&#34;&gt;3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/3.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/436795&#34;&gt;Joos van Cleve Netherlandish, Virgin and Child. ca 1525.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 1/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s the strangely mature reclining posture. Maybe it’s the little baby hand tightly gripping onto an orange despite the fact that this baby is very much asleep. But this baby overflows with some sort of latent psionic power that leaves me with a cold sweat. Despite his babyish body and calm face, this baby has got some great cursed energy. Final score: 3/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;35-2&#34;&gt;3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/4.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-obsessed-depiction-infant-jesus-middle-aged-man&#34;&gt;Duccio di Buoninsegna, Madonna and Child. 1290–1300 CE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 1/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This baby has got those classic homunculus proportions, which complement his exceptionally grey skin tone. I would love to see what he’s capable of in a few years once he gains a neck and can access some foundation. Final score: 3/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;335&#34;&gt;3.3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/5.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-obsessed-depiction-infant-jesus-middle-aged-man&#34;&gt;Barnaba da Modena, Madonna With Child. 1367.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 2/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 1/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This baby is attempting some attitude, but it’s toned down by his babylike features and neutral expression. He almost looks cute. He may be a winner in his own right, but this certainly isn’t the kind of cursed baby the crowds go wild for. Final score: 3.3/5. Next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;335-1&#34;&gt;3.3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/6.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/435765&#34;&gt;Workshop of Dieric Bouts, Virgin and Child. 1475–99. 
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 2/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This baby looks like the artist only realized he should be fat after he already drew in the skinny little body. He’s got the little baby fat dimples over a skinny legend frame. However, I do appreciate his little forehead curl. Final score: 3.3/5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;335-2&#34;&gt;3.3/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/7.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/461161&#34;&gt;Master of Guillaume Lambert, Virgin and Child. ca. 1485.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 4/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s blue. And maybe a bit stoned? Final score: 3.3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;45&#34;&gt;4/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/8.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mashable.com/2013/06/15/renaissance-babies/&#34;&gt;Master of the Life of Saint John the Baptist, Madonna and Child with Angels. Not dated.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 2/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By all accounts, this baby is an upgrade of Duccio di Buoninsegna’s. He may have lost that charming grey hue, but this guy excels in cursed long limbs and enough attitude to bat away his mother’s face. What looked almost loving in Buoninsegna’s baby’s posture looks upset and almost catty in this one. He’s got the diva energy, and we love to see it. Final score: 4/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;475&#34;&gt;4.7/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/9.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-obsessed-depiction-infant-jesus-middle-aged-man&#34;&gt;Maerten van Heemskerck, detail of St. Luke Painting the Virgin, 1532.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 4/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to give this baby a perfect 5/5 cursed rating right here right now. This baby has got everything: rippling muscles, a full head of perfectly waves hair, and an obvious predisposition for bloodlust. His mother is clearly holding him back from a battle he would most surely win. However, these chiseled bodies are a dime a dozen in early Renaissance art and that doesn’t exclude babies. As frighteningly ripped as this baby is, he’s not the only one, so I’m bumping him down on the style scale. Still, I’m giving this baby a near-perfect score because I’m almost sure he started - and ended - some European war. Final score: 4.7/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;465&#34;&gt;4.6/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/10.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/458956&#34;&gt;Bartolo di Fredi, The Adoration of the Magi. 1390.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 4/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely OBSESSED with what this baby’s bringing to the table. I hope he touches my forehead with his clammy little, fully articulated hand. Final score: 4.6/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;55&#34;&gt;5/5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/ugly-babies/11.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/437674&#34;&gt;Luca Signorelli (Luca d&amp;rsquo;Egidio di Luca di Ventura), Madonna and Child. ca. 1505–7.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportions: 1/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitude: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely feel disgusted by the energy this baby radiates. It’s not just cursed but filled with intentional malice. Please don’t stare at this baby for more than 3 seconds at a time. Final score: oh my god get it away from me i don’t care about totaling up the numbers this is a 5/5.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Arbitrary Ways to Stay Creative at Home </title>
      <link>/blog/7-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 21:13:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/7-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;7-arbitrary-ways-to-stay-creative-at-home&#34;&gt;7 Arbitrary Ways to Stay Creative at Home&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haley Arnold, Social Media Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2021, and COVID is still in full swing. With cities encouraging us to continue social distancing, work from home and limit our activity outside of the home, it can be hard to stay entertained and feel motivated. At this point we have all moved on from whipped coffee and sourdough bread, so here are 10 other ideas on how to be creative at home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn a Tik Tok dance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, you are not too old for Tik Tok! Challenge yourself to learn one of those 15 second dances you’re seeing all over the internet! Send it to your friends and challenge them to learn it as well. You don’t have to be a good dancer to appreciate the art of a 16 year old’s choreography, and believe it or not those bite sized dances prove to work up a sweat! Better yet, make up your own!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a music video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on your favorite song at the moment, break out the props, and have your main character moment. Film yourself lip syncing and feeling yourself in a few different areas of your house. Then breakout those editing skills you have from when you thought you were going to be a Youtube star back in middle school and work your magic. The worse quality, and more chaotic energy the better. You never know, you could receive a call from SZA asking you to star in her Good Days music video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try drag makeup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve binged all 13 seasons of RuPaul’s Drag Race, you should have a good understanding of how it’s done. Breakout the glue stick and fake eyelashes and get to painting. If you still don’t feel prepared, go watch all 5 seasons of All Stars and come back. Or follow one of Trixie Mattel’s many tutorials on Youtube. Don’t forget to contour that nose and glue down your wig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go for a walk and make up full life stories about the people who live in the houses you pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a little hard to people watch when there are no people to watch. But that doesn’t mean you can’t make up stories about imaginary people living in the houses you see on your neighborhood walk. Who are they? What are their relationships to each other? Sometimes you might get lucky and see someone in the yard that can give you a starting prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize your closet by color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this only sounds fun to me because I am a Virgo… Just remember ROY G BIV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make outfits for your pet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut holes in that old sock that’s been missing its pair for the last three years but you can’t bring yourself to get rid of, and turn it into a sweater for your guinea pig, rat, bunny, rat dog or other small animal. Or crochet or sew a gown for your dog. Fabric glue is a great alternative for those of us who are lacking the domestic skills of sewing or knitting. Our poor dogs are ready for us to go back to work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn a new language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare for those trips you’ve been dreaming about taking for the past 10 months, or brush up on those 4 years of a language you took in high school and somehow have forgotten all of. Or make up your own language with your roommates. After 10 months of being stuck in the house with them, I’d be surprised if you didn’t already have one (perhaps a non-verbal, body language, leave me alone glare, type of language).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature is out there! (and it can help with your health and creativity, too!)</title>
      <link>/blog/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:10:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nature-is-out-there-and-it-can-help-with-your-health-and-creativity-too&#34;&gt;Nature is out there! (and it can help with your health and creativity, too!)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peyton Farnum, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With  all the craziness that 2020 has brought, it can be difficult to  remember to take some time to care for yourself. Luckily, I am here to  inform you that one of the easiest ways to do so is remarkably simple:  spend some time outside!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature  is all around us. It is something that is irreplaceably beautiful in  our world, but it serves more than just aesthetic purpose. Spending two  hours a week outside is proven to have psychological benefits in more  ways than one.¹ Increased time spent in nature can promote a calm sense  of wellbeing, and can also help improve your mood and stimulate the  parts of your brain that control creativity.¹ Us creative people know  that whatever we can get our hands on to help us succeed is vital, and  luckily for us, it’s incredibly accessible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration is  abundant in the outdoor world. Plants, animals and landscapes make  incredible subjects for artwork, as they often come in beautiful shapes  and colors. Sketching some of these will help you sharpen your  observational drawing skills and provide a variety of texture to  replicate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun tip: collect flowers or leaves and press them in your sketchbook! They might make good use in a collage or other projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/peyton.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I  painted this back in 2018 during a trip to Nicaragua. I sat in the  shade near the edge of the sand and painted the remarkable visage of the  water and vegetation around me. In the hours I spent creating it, I  felt intensely serene&amp;ndash;every breath I took was crisp and all the sounds  of life around me kept a presence of calmness as I worked. It was one of  my favorite experiences of art-making, all because of the natural  environment I chose to surround myself with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let this serve as a  friendly reminder to leave our hobbit holes every once in a while and  soak up some quality natural atmosphere. Grab your paints, inks,  pencils, or any art making instrument of your choice and head to your  nearest outdoor location! Feel the grass, listen to the birds or wind,  take a load off under a tree and take some deep breaths. Commemorate the  trip by getting some enjoyable creative work done, or just take some  time to relax. Afterwards, you will hopefully feel more mentally sound  and prepared to tackle any obstacles that lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to take care of yourself and enjoy all that earth has to offer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference: Jim Robbins, Ecopsychology: How Immersion in Nature Benefits Your Health (Yale 360, 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Sincerity during Quarantine</title>
      <link>/blog/new-sincerity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:07:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-sincerity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;new-sincerity-during-quarantine&#34;&gt;New Sincerity during Quarantine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracie Neirynck, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art  changes throughout time, evolving to address each century’s unique  struggles and values. In an effort to retaliate against the cynicism of a  post-war era, modern writers began to pioneer a new age of writing  which they called New Sincerity. This era was founded upon the idea that  in modern times it was far more courageous to describe the subtle dust  and honesty of everyday life than it was to write about extreme emotion.  It rebelled against the idea that sentimentality was naive and instead  sought to express it. This idea appealed to me as I came to college.  Repulsed by the aftertaste of teenage angst on my tongue, I became  enchanted with the lingering notion that honesty could be a form of  rebellion. As the world began to shut down during quarantine, I wondered  if this idea would hold up in a time of isolation. I wondered if  sincerity would still be resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When  March reared its ugly head my fast-paced freshman year of college  became completely still, like that of many others. This stillness  bothered me. I felt utterly useless as I read each morning about the  thousands of people across the globe who were falling victim to a virus  which was completely indifferent to them. There was no real outlet to  express my frustration. It is hard to rebel against something which is  so indifferent. The only way I know how to rebel against indifference is  to be sincere. In a nation more ravaged with the virus than ever  before, the age of New Sincerity is more relevant now than it was before  quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zadie Smith demonstrates the ways in which art is an  instrument of sincerity in her short story, “Words and Music”. This  short story follows unique characters in distinct settings, every  character connected solely by their passion for art. Through these  characters she encapsulates the enduring beauty of artistic expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  story opens on a young girl scatting, using her voice to imitate the  tones of an instrument. The girl’s strange devotion to sounds and shapes  even if they lack linguistic meaning emphasizes the bizarre appeal of  art. Zadie Smith uses the meaninglessness of the sounds in this passage  in order to convey a lack of intention. This art is not trying to be  grandiose or profound. Rather, its purpose is simply to exist. Through  this Smith suggests that the beauty of music is created when it is born  for its own sake; without bragging of its melody or begging for an  audience. Similarly, the artist is most sincere when their art is  created from an inexplicable desire of expression, and it is this  relentless desire which Smith finds admirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see these  sentiments repeated as the narrative changes to follow a man without  legs who talks endlessly of disco. His enduring loyalty to music he can  no longer dance to is a testament to the stubborn admiration humans have  for music. This relentless love begs the question, what is it about  music that captures us? Why do we love it unconditionally? Zadie Smith  does not attempt to answer these questions and instead suggest that the  simple fact that humans love art so ardently is magnificent within  itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zadie Smith blurs the lines between identity and art in  her final scene. She describes an outdoor concert in which multitudes of  people gather to listen to a lone guitarist. The concert becomes a  near-supernatural affair as she describes the music surrounding the  people and the ways in which it hijacks their thoughts. Here, the main  character entertains the idea of a purely auditory world. How would she  distinguish herself from other sounds? Would they merely mesh together  to form a convoluted kind of symphony? By stripping away the material  world and leaving only sound behind, Zadie Smith confronts the ways in  which one&amp;rsquo;s voice is tangled in the music of the world. Identity then  becomes blurred with art, and only regains its independence through  consciousness. Once again, art enables honesty of identity, and it is  through this honesty that these characters find a sliver of catharsis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What  Zadie Smith ultimately digs at in “Words and Music” is the idea that  art is the product of an intangible itch on the soul. You scratch  endlessly, you bleed onto paper, but your soul will always itch.  Although never perfect, within art there exists a shadow of honesty, and  this is why I cling to it so fervently. It is why during this pandemic  my headphones felt as natural as hair and I had to clear my bed of books  each night. I think that art, no matter how sloppy or unedited it is,  is rebellion. I think each time you sing, dance, or draw simply because  you want to, you are voicing a silent “fuck you” to indifference. It is  through sincerity of expression that we can retaliate against everything  threatening vulnerability. I use art to cope because underneath  metaphors and melodies art gives me a chance to be sincere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we  head into winter and what will likely be a few more challenging months, I  want to leave you with my favorite quote by Zadie Smith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He who  sings to himself without earbuds is especially precious to me now, like  hearing the song of a bird long thought extinct.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it reminds you that art is never foolish and encourages you to create with abandon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Miss Being a Kid</title>
      <link>/blog/being-a-kid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 21:01:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/being-a-kid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-miss-being-a-kid&#34;&gt;I Miss Being a Kid&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casey Forest, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes
college is the place where we lose it—it not referring to virginity, 
house keys, parental respect, or mental stability. Hard as it is to 
admit, I myself have lost it more than once here, despite the fact that 
I’ve spent a lot of money to become an undergrad and curate it, in hopes
of making it marketable. This month we were asked to talk about 
creative coping, and I’m here to announce that I have been doing no such
thing—not in the pandemic, not in the summer, not even at any point in 
my college career. I have had tunnel vision since maybe Antiquity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There
is an indefinable creative quality that lives its life very gently, 
very quietly in that back of our heads. It is slippery and shy as an 
eggshell in cake batter. It’s kind of an asshole: it doesn’t care that 
you haven’t written in three months or that a residency application 
deadline is tonight. To get it to clock in, everything must be just 
right, it has to feel safe; the stars must align, the to-do list must be
full (but not too full), the head must be clear. I do not encounter 
these conditions very often. So it is often absent for me now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This
is the point where being able to define it might be important. I am not
talking about happiness, or creativity, or passion, or motivation, or 
even the want to make something. In my mind, it is something that 
cohabitated with my brain, happily, until I graduated high school. For 
me, it was an organic, almost frenzied connection to writing. I would 
come home from school every day (every! day! it baffles me now) and sit 
at my dad’s old white computer to write for hours, with no desire to 
pause or snack or do anything other than write. This is the period in my
life that defined me as a writer; even when I stopped being able to do 
that, I still considered myself one. In retrospect, it was probably 
still lurking in the back of my head, refusing to surface, waiting for 
me to forget about it so it could come back, unnoticed, to rekindle 
something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is super specific. I do not expect anyone to 
be able to relate to it. But for the sake of making someone feel seen, I
have compiled a checklist to help us recognize it, since I believe it 
bops around and manifests itself in different ways; ways which might 
reassure you that it has not left you, even if you’re having a hard time
creating right now; or might remind you of the park you went to as a 
child; or that might make your eyes glaze over until you hit the end of 
the list or, god forbid, click back to your Instagram feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will sit down and pick a movie. It will not take you eighty years to do it.*   When there were still theaters, you would walk out, sneakers muffled on the carpet, shocked that it was still daytime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://cicadacreativemag.com/issuepage.html&#34;&gt;Artist Animal&lt;/a&gt; makes you want to swim to the bottom of the ocean, immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last year, when a friend got up from the café table to refill their coffee,you doodled something on the back of the dirty napkin. It was a poem or a
honeybee or an exceptionally straight line. You felt the need to put it
in your pocket, and now it lives in some drawer somewhere, and if youwent to find it right now you would feel alarmed at how brutally honestit is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Pinterest boards are clustered. You cling to Mori Kei skirts or Swedish interior decorating until you don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could not separate the fire from the heat, even if you tried.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While you’re falling asleep, while your mind is doing whatever minds do inthe forty minutes it takes you to start dreaming, you could be joltedback awake by remembering you haven’t wished your uncle a happy Friday,even though it is Tuesday and you haven’t spoken to him since he taggedyou in a post about nephews he found on the Cows are Angels in DisguiseFacebook page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, what I’m rambling on about is a 
sense of presence that precedes an ability to create. Personally, I do 
not think higher education (or pandemics, or unruly elections, or 
natural disasters) is all that conducive to the kind of presence that 
offers a place for the spontaneous content that is easiest to make. 
Understand that I am not saying it is impossible to make something 
non-academic without it; I am merely trying to articulate something 
that’s been bothering me since my daily word count became my monthly 
word count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our present moment, which is terrible, we need 
every support we can get to create something external. My fiction 
workshop professor would implore you to write (or draw, or needle-felt, 
whatever) what needs to be written (drawn, felted, whatever), especially
now; to offer that space to someone else who might need it, or even to 
offer it to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But trying to create right now is really 
hard. It is really hard to sit down and stare at a blank page and 
remember how easy it used to be. It’s hard to come to terms with the 
fact that all your creating goes into files for school which you might 
not ever look at again, that you’ve run out of energy, that everyone is 
telling you how important it is to keep making in a time when the most 
organic parts of us are hibernating. It’s hard to pivot an entire 
identity on creation and exist in a time where it’s impossible to 
process what’s going on, and more impossible still to face the guilt of 
distracting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m only here to tell you that coping looks
very different depending on the day, the hour. Sometimes it’s great to 
force out something creative and be proud that you can, even with the 
absence of it; sometimes all we can do is browse the Documentary section
on Netflix unfeelingly and be a little inspired but mostly jealous that
someone created such a pretty film in a time like this. I’m also here 
to remind you to look for it; to not be upset that it might be hiding 
again; to console it, and console yourself. It is not gone; it couldn’t 
possibly be, it loves you too much; and if you can’t create right now, 
okay, then maybe you have the time to roll out a welcome mat and dust 
the curtains should it decide to tiptoe back some morning soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Montage</title>
      <link>/blog/modern-montage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:59:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/modern-montage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;modern-montage&#34;&gt;Modern Montage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molly Flood, Creative Team Member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protest has also been a prevalent theme in art throughout the years. This timeline explores art that addresses injustice and inequality in the past 100 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world sat in their home over the past year, the passage of time became monotonous for many. People all over the world experienced lockdown to different degrees and had unique ways of coping. The reemergence of Montage film editing flooded Tik Tok with unique perspectives of how the newfound time in between can be romanticized and documented. In popular film today, Montage is most commonly used to represent the passing of time, but Tik Tok creators, building upon inspiration from each other, have a new take on this style. The Tik Tok video shooting platform encourages short snappy videos which have led to Montage style vlogs, fashion, and art videos in a way that montage has not been used for before. Creating and watching content of day to day life and creativity serves as escapism and comfort to a generation trapped inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVrnw6/&#34;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVrnw6/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creator, Judita (@judenyk) uses her page to create space for the moments in between, montaging past and present moments to highlight the beauty in the simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVfb2S/&#34;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVfb2S/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@mi4k3lly replicates experimental Montage methods with a modern and casual twist. I have selected this page to represent the experimental and new creators coming out of the creative medium of Tik Tok. Using household items, common sounds, and a phone camera to record @mi4k3lly is still able to create something unique and unsettling about the experience of passing time in a dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVBUE1/&#34;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVVBUE1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taitù’s videos (@illstealyourgirlfriend), hold a laid back, effortlessly cool appearance due to the subtle yet intentional Montage technique present. Her shots are often connected by the color, or small details connecting her outfits. Taitù films dressing and styling intentionally,seamlessly connecting Montage and fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVV6ks6/&#34;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMJVV6ks6/&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gillian’s content, (@shoegremlin) features Montage that follows a similarly slow pace flow of living inside and being outside with friends. The placement of the clips seems completely interchangeable, replicating the placeless mood of the time passed this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small social elements of the classroom that I miss, a comic.</title>
      <link>/blog/social-elements-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:34:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/social-elements-classroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-social-elements-of-the-classroom-that-i-miss-a-comic&#34;&gt;Small social elements of the classroom that I miss, a comic.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Dunn, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss sitting in front of a real person and hearing them lecture, but even more than that I miss the ten minutes before class where I could talk to my peers, catch up on current world news, and orient myself with where everyone else was in their projects (was I behind?). I’ve had no trouble getting access to lectures and asking questions through zoom, but I miss the sense of community formed by a classroom joke. Education is such a social thing, which virtual education just can’t replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class1.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class2.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class3.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class4.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class5.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/class/class6.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proctoring software is a nightmare for students. It doesn’t have to be this way.</title>
      <link>/blog/proctoring-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:28:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/proctoring-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;proctoring-software-is-a-nightmare-for-students-it-doesnt-have-to-be-this-way&#34;&gt;Proctoring software is a nightmare for students. It doesn’t have to be this way.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As
you all know: COVID. In response to the lack of in-person interaction, 
many colleges and universities have begun to use proprietary software to
ensure students do not cheat during exams, most often ProctorU, 
Proctorio, and ExamSoft. I take 3 issues with this development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.) This is spyware.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you require students to install software that quite literally watches them, that is spyware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Spyware
describes software with malicious behavior that aims to gather 
information about a person or organization and send such information to 
another entity in a way that harms the user; for example by violating 
their privacy or endangering their device&amp;rsquo;s security.” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spyware&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern
tech’s propensity for obsessive surveillance has become increasingly 
difficult to combat and virtually impossible to avoid. However, one 
would hope higher institutions would advocate for things like data 
privacy and personal agency. Instead, the director of academic testing 
services at Utah State University lightheartedly described Proctorio as 
“sort of like spyware that we just legitimize.” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/01/online-proctoring-college-exams-coronavirus/&#34;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;)
The University of Arizona’s assistant director of technology  insisted 
students don’t mind because “they know this is an expectation because 
their professors put it out there.” Perhaps unsurprisingly, the student 
body says otherwise. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21232777/examity-remote-test-proctoring-online-class-education&#34;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt;)  Additionally, the chief executive of Proctorio reflected on the situation with a dystopian, “we’re the police.” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/01/online-proctoring-college-exams-coronavirus/&#34;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I
could spiral into a separate tangent about how the US obsession with 
policing and instinct to punish accelerates the meritocratic rot of late
stage capitalism under collaborative neoliberal and fascist rule, but 
suffice to say that no academic software should ever be comparing itself
to law enforcement. That’s how dystopian horror movies start. Putting 
aside this horrendously inappropriate take, violating student privacy is
a pattern—schools force us to engage with abusive proprietary software 
every day. Whether it’s opting us into a relationship with Google via 
school Gmail accounts, forcing students to have accounts with Adobe 
Creative Cloud as a requisite for even being able to engage with a 
course, or holding office hours via Microsoft Teams, there is an 
insidious drip of our data that is all being funneled through people who
want to profit from it. All of these companies have been revealed to be
astonishingly abusive with data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/2019/07/22/tech/google-street-view-privacy-lawsuit-settlement/index.html&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/google-gmail-data-sharing-email-inbox-privacy-scandal-a8548941.html&#34;&gt;alone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnet.com/news/google-sued-over-keeping-location-data-amid-privacy-concerns/&#34;&gt;would&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2019/06/23/google-confirms-creepy-new-privacy-problem/#6587d31f9d8b&#34;&gt;take&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tomshardware.com/news/google-wifi-street-cars-spy-lawsuit-settlement,39998.html&#34;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-exposed-user-data-feared-repercussions-of-disclosing-to-public-1539017194&#34;&gt;entire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politico.eu/article/google-data-breach-privacy-data-protection/&#34;&gt;new&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-privacy-lawsuit-idUSKBN23933H&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; to cover (4 lawsuits and counting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I
don’t expect universities to be a beacon of free and open-source 
software, especially given how frankly inconvenient most FOSS is. But I 
also don’t expect them to gleefully make it worse. Proctor software 
requires a webcam to view (and, usually, tour) a student’s living space 
and often uses biometrics to track their physical motion; it often 
features facial recognition and eye tracking. It also records the event 
and human proctors may be able to remotely control the student’s 
machine. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/01/online-proctoring-college-exams-coronavirus/&#34;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;)
It seems almost absurd to have to explain the Orwellian nature of this 
type of surveillance, but in case this wasn’t clear: allowing for-profit
companies to record and monitor students in their private living spaces
because they might look up a Calculus formula is absolutely unhinged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.)
It isn’t an effective measure for cheating and does not account for 
students with disabilities or, really, the majority of people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One
of the most infamous features of this type of software is that it 
tracks eye movement and physical motion. These are, perhaps, pretty easy
behaviors to latch onto as signs of academic dishonesty. But, as is 
often the case, the easiest path is also the laziest and least 
thoughtful. The assumption that darting eyes and excessive motion are 
indicators of dishonesty is a lazy one that perpetuates ableist beliefs 
and assumptions.  Students with ADHD may have a difficult time sitting 
still or staring directly at the monitor. Students with anxiety may need
periods of time to readjust, perhaps closing their eyes to re-center. A
student on the autism spectrum may need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimming&#34;&gt;stim&lt;/a&gt;
during an exam. Students with chronic pain and/or fatigue may need to 
take breaks to stretch or struggle with uncomfortable seating (hi, 
that’s me.) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/29/style/testing-schools-proctorio.html&#34;&gt;As one student reported&lt;/a&gt;,
she struggles with tics, particularly in stressful situations (such as 
exams), which puts her in a situation where she is being recorded in a 
vulnerable moment as she struggles with her disability, which she 
describes as embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even neurotypical students often 
fidget (clicking a pen, shaking a leg, etc.) It’s a very normal response
to stress and hyper-concentration. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22711579/&#34;&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2010/11/101115155756.htm&#34;&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://slate.com/human-interest/2017/05/johns-hopkins-memory-game-shows-how-motion-affects-memory-and-cognition.html&#34;&gt;studies &lt;/a&gt;indicate
that motion can be an effective tool to aid memory retrieval and 
clearer cognition. There is no reason to flag this as a suspicious or 
negative behavior, either in person or virtually. The only reason to 
discourage this behavior is for their benefit&amp;ndash;it is much easier to 
identify any behavior other than the strictly prescribed one than it is 
to actually prioritize all students’ learning. Conventional academic 
settings are notoriously unfriendly to neurodivergent students and are 
often directly detrimental to the professed goals of teaching and 
learning. This is very much an institutional problem. It is just even 
more glaring and naked when distilled in this way&amp;ndash;when given the choice
between letting students learn comfortably (requiring some 
recalibration of course material) and forcing disabled students to be 
recorded by a software that is trained to view them as inherently 
suspicious, universities chose the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To refocus and 
summarize: This software strips students of effective coping tools to 
take a test and hinders their academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we’ve 
identified two ways this software works to the detriment of students and
have identified zero ways it works to our benefit. At this point, we 
must ask: “Who does this serve?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.) This is a byproduct of institutional laziness that does not value its undergraduate students.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We
have access to all the information we could ever need to perform our 
tasks competently, rendering many old testing styles archaic and 
impractical. Of course, we should have some working knowledge, but most 
of us will not be in situations where we have 2 minutes to recall the 
types of fault lines of the North American plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It demonstrates
a broader issue: universities take their undergraduate students for 
granted; they fleece us for money we don’t have under the pretense that 
good education costs good money, then refuse to intervene when they do 
not deliver on that promise. We’re forced to spend inordinate amounts of
money on textbooks—an 88% increase between 2006 and 2016 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/3/6/18252322/college-textbooks-cost-expensive-pearson-cengage-mcgraw-hill&#34;&gt;Vox&lt;/a&gt;)—and
additional equipment like clickers (which are usually just used to take
attendance). We have little recourse when our professors (especially 
tenured professors) implement abusive practices. But we make these 
institutions run. Without undergraduate students, every single one of 
these universities would go under. The institutional arrogance and 
entitlement seems to grow every day, becoming harder and harder to 
ignore. But we&amp;ndash;and more importantly, they&amp;ndash;know college is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/social-mobility-memos/2014/02/11/does-college-really-improve-social-mobility/&#34;&gt;the single most important tool for upward class mobility&lt;/a&gt;.
As the casualties of late stage capitalism’s death rattle, we have no 
choice. It’s why they do it&amp;ndash;they know they’ll get away with it. They 
know we have nowhere else to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this specific context, I 
understand the burden of reconfiguring a course is not an easy one to 
shoulder and I do not expect professors to suddenly have all the 
answers. However, by introducing this software, the professor shifts 
this burden to this student&amp;ndash;again. It is not our burden to bear&amp;ndash;again.
We’re struggling as well—there is no need to make it worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some
of my fellow Cicadas pointed out I left this on a fairly depressing 
note. Although I am determinedly cynical, I don’t think there’s any harm
in sharing some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proctoring software is generally used for 
summative assessments, which evaluates student learning at a given 
benchmark, like a midterm or a final exam. These are high stakes, which 
means there is a high incentive to cheat, hence the proctors. Formative 
assessments are lower stakes, things like a quick summary of a lecture 
or a mini-quiz. Formative assessments aid learning and summative 
assessments measure learning. Conventional wisdom says both are 
necessary. A trickle of research has indicated that this may not be the 
case and this teacher makes&lt;a href=&#34;http://fearlessteachers.com/what-if-there-were-no-summative-assessments/&#34;&gt; a very compelling case&lt;/a&gt; as for why summative assessments might not even be necessary anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That
in mind, the most logical way to resolve this proctoring issue would be
to eliminate time-based, closed note summative tests. There are many 
ways to achieve this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution #1: More (formative) testing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I
think almost everyone can identify with the “cramming for a test” 
experience. You sit down at 11:00 PM to engage with the material for the
first time before your 8:00 AM exam. If you’re like me, maybe you’re 
only just now reading the textbook (oops). You open Quizlet and stare at
the screen till your eyes hurt. Is it too late to email the professor a
clarification question? You sleep for 3 hours, remorsefully wobbling 
your way through the test as you desperately chug the dregs of your 
coffee. You leave the room and feel overwhelming relief. You pass the 
test and learn almost nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry L. Roediger III, a famous cognitive psychologist known for his research on memory, asserts the following: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologicalscience.org/observer/learning-through-testing&#34;&gt;fast learning leads to fast forgetting&lt;/a&gt;.
Cramming is popular because it works. At least, long enough to get 
through the test. His study reveals that self-testing is an incredibly 
effective tool for learning, but that it is not leveraged in a 
productive way. He elaborates on a concept known as the “testing effect”
and studies better testing practices, all of which you can find &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1745-6916.2006.00012.x&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically,
he asserts that one day of intense formative assessments was so 
effective for learning that it enabled the student to survive a 
summative assessment. In other words, many times, a cramming situation 
occurs because the formative assessments either did not happen or they 
were not effective,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to implement/Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quizzes
can be embedded into lecture videos using Canvas. Every lecture couldbe split into multiple videos, each one with graded, embedded quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could be a weekly quiz that goes over lecture material. Maybe this quiz has 2-3 attempts and records the highest score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution #2: No memory-based testing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If
summative exams are really necessary, there are other ways to measure 
mastery of the material. One could argue that assessments such as 
recitals and other performances require a component of memory, but 
generally, performance-based summative assessments are an accumulation 
of all you’ve learned and retain the pressure of a traditional exam 
without requiring a proctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever taken notes so 
desperately you didn’t actually absorb what was said? Have you ever just
listened to a lecture and been surprised at how much you absorbed? Our 
fear of not remembering something we’ll need on an exam can be extremely
distracting. However, if you can focus on the lecture completely 
without being distracted, you can have a more meaningful recollection of
the material. Maybe you don’t remember Crime and Punishment was 
published in 1866, but you do remember that it was published in a 
serialization for 12 months in the 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement/Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essays
take the place of traditional exams. Instead of a time-based huntthrough the treasure trove of young adult memory, a student can taketheir time to sort through the information they’ve been presented andcreate a unique response. This does, of course, have its own host ofchallenges and should be treated carefully, but essays could just aseasily measure mastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps a class could be conductedalmost entirely through discussions and direct engagement. After everysingle lecture, you post a summary of what you learned with 3 questions.
This is a type of formative testing that could replace mini-quizzes and
other memory based assessments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Brief History of Protest Art in America</title>
      <link>/blog/protest-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:52:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/protest-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-very-brief-history-of-protest-art-in-america&#34;&gt;A Very Brief History of Protest Art in America&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haley Arnold, Publications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protest has also been a prevalent theme in art throughout the years. This timeline explores art that addresses injustice and inequality in the past 100 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1931 - Diego Rivera, Detail of “The Uprising”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexican Muralists, such as Diego Rivera, created fresco style murals in North America to revolt against tyrannical industrialization, and give a voice to the silenced Mexican-Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1942 - Gordon Parks, American Gothic, Washington, D.C.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parks was a photojournalist who documented the lives of Black Americans to highlight civil rights, racial inequality, and poverty. He aimed to highlight communities and social issues in order to effect change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/3.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1944 - Tokyo Miyatake, Untitled (Opening Image from Valediction)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyatake and his family were relocated to a Japanese internment camp in California in 1942 under the Roosevelt administration. Though photography was outlawed, Miyatake built a makeshift camera with a smuggled lens and box to shoot daily life at the camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/4.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1974 - Ana Mendieta, Untitled&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Cuban migrant, Mendieta combined her body and land in her performances and installations to highlight the nature of gender and the environment. Her works demonstrate the relationship between feminism and the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/5.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1985 - Guerilla Girls are Founded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guerilla Girls are a group of anonymous art activists whose mission is to highlight women artists and artists of color while exposing the white male dominance in the art world. They research statistics and facts behind some of the biggest art establishments and use irony and humor in their propaganda to expose these truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/6.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1987 - Donald Moffett, He Kills Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moffett made this poster to highlight the failure of Reagan’s administration to respond to the AIDS epidemic. The president remained silent regarding the epidemic for a long time, ultimately causing the death of many Americans especially among the LGBTQ+ community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/7.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1989 - Keith Haring, Ignorance= Fear / Silence = Death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A street artist from New York, Haring used his work to advocate for the AIDS crisis and give a voice to the LGBTQ+ community who were silenced at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/8.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 - Theaster Gates, Minority Majority&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gates uses fire hoses in his work to speak on the history of race in the United States and violence against black Americans. By using fire hoses, his art alludes to the violent use of such tools towards the peaceful civil rights protesters. Though the same materials may no longer be used, this violence is still prominent today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/9.png#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 - Kara Walker, A Subtlety…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker’s sculpture features a larger than life sphinx figure made entirely of sugar, portraying a racist stereotype of black women. The use of sugar and installing the sculpture in a form or sugar factory alludes to the history of slavery in the industry in the United States, and the objectification and fetishization of black women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/protest/10.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2019 - Nan Goldin &amp;amp; P.A.I.N, Die In at the V&amp;amp;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldin founded P.A.I.N (Prescription Addiction Intervention Now), and began “die-in” demonstrations in front of art establishments around the world to call attention to the opioid epidemic in the United States, and the involvement of the Slacker family who profited highly off of OxyContin and were major benefactors of some of the largest art institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.format.com/magazine/features/art/brief-history-protest-art&#34;&gt;https://www.format.com/magazine/features/art/brief-history-protest-art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2017/sep/06/a-brief-history-of-protest-art-from-the-1940s-until-now-whitney-new-york&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2017/sep/06/a-brief-history-of-protest-art-from-the-1940s-until-now-whitney-new-york&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://magazine.artland.com/the-art-of-a-movement-protest-art/&#34;&gt;https://magazine.artland.com/the-art-of-a-movement-protest-art/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufactured Consent: Five Filters of Media Bias</title>
      <link>/blog/manufacturing-consent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:44:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/manufacturing-consent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;manufactured-consent-five-filters-of-media-bias&#34;&gt;Manufactured Consent: Five Filters of Media Bias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an era of political turmoil and and misinformation, it is more important than ever to critically evaluate and critique the news media we consume. Even traditionally trustworthy news sources are not immune to bias and manipulation. Not only must we be vigilant with the accuracy of the information we consume, we must also be aware of what we’re not being told&amp;ndash;what context is being left out? What stories are being buried? What stories are being pushed? What loaded language is being used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/manufacturing-consent.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/manufacturing-consent1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A productive tool I’ve found to examine the news I consume is a propaganda model advanced by Noam Chomsky and Edward S. Horton in their book, &lt;em&gt;Manufacturing Consent: The Political Economy of the Mass Media.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video this graphic is based off of is &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D34LGPIXvU5M&amp;amp;t=N2VkN2Y3MWIxZTMzOWVlOTIyODQ4NTA1MmI4ZTgwNGVjOTg4MzA4ZCxiZTZiMzlhNDJiMzAzMWRlM2Q3YzNiOGNjY2M5MGRlNjRlMDI3MDk4&amp;amp;ts=1606523076&#34;&gt;Al Jazeera’s short video&lt;/a&gt;, narrated by Amy Goodman of Democracy Now. Vectors can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vecteezy.com%2Fvector-art%2F151045-free-news-vectors&amp;amp;t=N2MzOTAxMjliOTVmZTcyYTAwMDY5Y2JhNzczNGM1ZDM4NWQ4MDU3NSwxYzQxNjk2MWYxMDg5ZDUyYzc4ZWM4MjNiNjAxNDhhYWJiMWQyMzEz&amp;amp;ts=1606523076&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Black Designers You Need to Follow</title>
      <link>/blog/20-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:23:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/20-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;20-black-designers-you-need-to-follow&#34;&gt;20 Black Designers You Need to Follow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reilly Webster, Director of Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love to imagine design as the industry of the future–innovative, inclusive, progressive.  However, this field is just as prone to racial inequality as any other industry in America, if not moreso. Just check out page 14 of the 2019 AIGA Design Census. Because of this, it is imperative that we begin to recenter the conversation. White designers in the industry have an obligation to elevate our Black peers. You can start by checking out the amazing designers and organizations that I’ve listed in this Quick List for Cicada’s September newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 collectives striving to diversify the design world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.badguild.info/&#34;&gt;Black Artists + Designers Guild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://designjustice.org/&#34;&gt;Design Justice Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revisionpath.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;Revision Path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blackspace.org/&#34;&gt;BlackSpace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a&gt;FRESH Speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freshspeakers.com/&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blackswho.design/&#34;&gt;Blacks Who Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wherearetheblackdesigners.com/&#34;&gt;Where Are the Black Designers?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aiga.org/diversity-equity-inclusion&#34;&gt;AIGA’s Diversity and Inclusion Initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aagd.co/&#34;&gt;African American Graphic Designers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsgnrswrkshp.com/&#34;&gt;The Designer’s Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 individuals + projects to check out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vocaltype.co/&#34;&gt;Vocal Type Co.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.100blackfemales.com/&#34;&gt;100 Black Females Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://projectnaptural.com/posters/&#34;&gt;Project Naptural&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/199155629&#34;&gt;Kaitlyn Chandler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.noisemakerdesign.com/&#34;&gt;Noisemaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adehogue.com/&#34;&gt;Adé Hogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brandonbreaux.com/&#34;&gt;Brandon Breaux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gailycurl.com/&#34;&gt;Gail Anderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jessicabellamy.design/&#34;&gt;Jessica Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.28blacks.com/&#34;&gt;The 28 Days of Black Designers Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/designers.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration by Reilly Webster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unity of Form in Layli Long Soldier&#39;s &#39;Obligations 2&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/unity-of-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 20:19:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/unity-of-form/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-unity-of-form-in-layli-long-soldiers-obligations-2&#34;&gt;The Unity of Form in Layli Long Soldier&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Obligations 2&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herman Luis Chavez, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layli Long Soldier’s “Obligations 2” is adventurous with form. This poem confronts us with choices we must make as the reader; we can take a path through the middle, or through the edges, or a combination of both. We can read top to bottom, and we can read left to right. We can read and re-read and re-read and find a new poem each time. Whatever we do, we’re presented with the enigma of choice. No matter how we do it, Long Soldier restricts the specific words, and sometimes where we start and end. I believe that in writing this poem, Soldier gives us a hot take on unity: no matter how we choose to roam, we end up coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poem: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/149976/obligations-2&#34;&gt;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/149976/obligations-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Soldier demonstrates choice to us through her form. She gives us 9 lines, but they aren’t equal. Spanning from one phrase to five, we have both a maximum and a minimum amount of paths to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are, however, some steady truths to the poem. It begins with “As we” and it ends with “across our faces”; noticeably, in both instances, there is a sense of communality, where the speaker of the poem identifies with others. We can infer that this community is the poem’s reader, from the structure of the poem and the agency that it gives the reader. Long Soldier also gives us one line with the same phrase: “the grief” that repeats four times in the sixth line. We have to face the grief, and we have to face it together. Long Soldier doesn’t give us a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, everywhere else, we can decide, even if only between a few options. Here’s my favorite path: “As we embrace the present we begin to accept the grief we wield into light across our faces.” This path gives me strength. The phrases with “embrace,” “accept,” and “wield,” combined with Long Soldier’s communal references, make me as a reader feel empowered to take on the grief laid out for me. There are other options, though, each with their own emotion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As we resist the past we fail to accept the grief we bury as ash across our faces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As we embrace the future we struggle to find the grief we shift into light across our faces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on, and on, and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, we don’t have a subject for our grief. Is it the world? Is it ourselves? It is something completely unexpected, such as a single rotted fruit? Or something more personal to Long Soldier, like a recently deceased loved one? There seems to be a totality to Long Soldier’s poem even if her subject remains elusive. The shape of her poem gives us a hint, though: a diamond. It is a precise shape, suggesting at the very least that there is a direction to the poem. Also, as a diamond, it suggests a sort of pressure that results in its current shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this poem as a call to join in unity to overcome suffering. I see that “Obligations 2” tells us that although we experience grief collectively, we each have different ways of experiencing it, and we have certain choices we can make even if others are tied to our community. I think this is useful for us, especially now. We are suffering through a pandemic. Through an election. Through large, worldly events we can’t control. We are in our own 2020 diamond, taking our own paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all comes down to this: we’re doing it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, choice is both given and taken. Layli Long Soldier engages with unity in different ways: I encourage you to think about the ways that you might read “Obligations 2,” and to use the following as a prompt for your own creative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this poem, Layli Long Soldier uses the diamond structure and different pathways to suggest choice even while maintaining community and grief as centerpieces of the poem. Write your own “diamond” poem, with two consistent strains. Like Long Soldier, see how you can give agency to your reader even as you present them with certain boundaries to remain within as they read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Pandemic: The Worldwide Increase in Domestic Abuse</title>
      <link>/blog/shadow-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:07:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/shadow-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-shadow-pandemic-the-worldwide-increase-in-domestic-abuse&#34;&gt;The Shadow Pandemic: The Worldwide Increase in Domestic Abuse&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katrina Clasen, Design Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When global lockdowns were put into place, the world felt a little safer with the pandemic seemingly contained; however, closed doors and 24/7 confinement bred a much more sinister affliction. The UN has depicted the worldwide increase in domestic violence as a &amp;ldquo;shadow pandemic&amp;rdquo; parallel to COVID-19, saying cases of domestic abuse during the pandemic have increased by 20 percent.These numbers can only reflect the reported cases. Stress and isolation generate incendiary tensions and an absence of privacy subjects many survivors to more intimate scrutiny by their abuser, making it hard to reach out for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only in the last few months, news sources and media outlets have begun to touch on the damage quarantine has caused in relation to domestic violence. Unfortunately, domestic abuse has only worsened as time ticks on.technological advances and financial dependency have become the harbingers of intimate abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology can essentially become a system of remote control. Some abusers will hack into home networks like Nest to blast music through home sound systems or jack the thermostat to uninhabitable temperatures, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/06/01/860739417/domestic-abuse-can-escalate-in-pandemic-and-continue-even-if-you-get-away&#34;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;). This can even be done when the victim is not at home, driving up electrical bills—here, technology, mental abuse, and financial abuse intersect. Though technology and money have become primary weapons for abusers to utilize, closeness has also become harmful. The introduction of tight living quarters and intimate surveillance that lockdowns produce has only worsened the already devastating living conditions for those at risk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the abuse adapts to lockdown conditions, concerned community members have changed how they offer aid. During the eight-week lockdown, people in West Bank stood on their balconies banging pots and pans to let vulnerable women know that their homes were open to them. In the Thar Desert in India, community volunteers set up a hotline that still takes dozens of calls a day and organizes food deliveries that allow volunteers to check in regularly with these women, so they know they are not trapped alone. During the one-month lockdown in Houston, Texas, a group of students used social media and dressed in denim to signal that women could approach them if they needed help. Volunteers deliver food to dozens of vulnerable women who have been in touch with messages placed inside bread bags provide information on where they can get help if they need it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the globe, from the balconies of West Bank to the bread bags in our homes, communities are coming together to combat the ravaging shadow pandemic. Instagram and WhatsApp have become vehicles for susceptible women to connect with outside sources who are willing to help. Yet governments fundamentally neglected to prepare for the manner in which the new public health measures would create opportunities for abusers to terrorize their victims. Now, many are struggling to offer services to those who are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic crises have put escaping on hold. Divorce proceedings are postponed until months later and finding new housing during the outbreak is proven difficult. Not only has the lack of global governmental preparation caused chaos for those living through the pandemic crisis, it has cut off avenues of escape for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institutions that should protect victims from abuse at home, several that are fragile and underfunded to begin with, are now straining to respond to the amplified need. Nevertheless, similar to the reaction to the infection itself, the delays reveal that irreparable harm may already have happened. Studies show that abusers are bound to hurt their partners and others in the wake of personal emergencies, including lost positions or major financial difficulties. With COVID-19 desolating the economy, such predicaments are bound to become much more frequent. The isolation has similarly devastated support networks, making it far more challenging for victims to get help or escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus has demonstrated the significance of local communities and the strength that comes from looking after one another, but it has also amplified the danger that occurs behind closed doors. Although many global lockdowns are easing, the World Health Organization warns countries to be on alert for a second wave of COVID-19 illnesses. As the world’s political and administrative climate has only begun initiatives to protect and support domestic abuse victims, a second wave of lockdowns will be debilitating. As allies, we cannot simply promise our support to those suffering from domestic violence. Like all acts of just change, we must actively defend and assist those who are at risk.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE INFORMATION AND RESOURCES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(provided by The National Coalition Against Domestic Violence)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://assets.speakcdn.com/assets/2497/covid_19_resources_by_topic.pdf?1585929833746&#34;&gt;Finding Resources/Resource Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://assets.speakcdn.com/assets/2497/domestic_violence-2020080709350855.pdf?1596828650457&#34;&gt;More on domestic violence in the United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncadv.org/covid-19-and-domestic-violence&#34;&gt;More on COVID-19 and Domestic Violence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncadv.org/support-ncadvs-covid-19-response&#34;&gt;Support NCADV&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 Response Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Have to Say about what Marx Would Have to Say about Capitalism and COVID-19</title>
      <link>/blog/marx-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 19:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/marx-covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-i-have-to-say-about-what-marx-would-have-to-say-about-capitalism-and-covid-19&#34;&gt;What I Have to Say about what Marx Would Have to Say about Capitalism and COVID-19&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casey Forest, Content Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we live is a mess. It’s a convoluted, poorly meshed, dig-until-your-hands-break country. It was a rug ripped out from under those who called it home, and now it is a capitalist petri dish. It’s hard to agree on things here, even with ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In middle school, a teacher once asked our class what we thought made a successful person. We were so cute – we said things like stability, kindness, helpfulness. Easy question; success was bred into us from the start. It was instinct more than desire. That was before we knew we would probably never be homeowners. And then the teacher asked us to name people we thought were successful. If we were not so stuffed on what was being fed to us, we would have said, my mother. The postman. You, Ms. Newman, for being here on such short salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can guess what we said. Who was successful, that we knew of? Of course it wasn’t Mom, who budgeted all year for a vacation in a town an hour away. It was Gates. Bezos. J.K. Rowling. It was such a shameless, unknowing sort of flip. To be successful and be seen as successful were two different things. Now I think back on it and feel just as confused as I did then. Succeed, the verb, the closing argument from my parent’s College Speech, was a euphemism for amass wealth. Or, even worse, it meant align your values with the rich on the off chance it works this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the opinion essay on collective values, capitalism, and the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/marx-covid2.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean to be overdramatic. But I am not sure how many soft ways there are to say that a capitalist system such as this was not ever meant to survive a global pandemic. My reasoning, simply put, is this: you cannot be valued as a moral person in a system that only values you in your capacity to labor. This has become glaringly obvious in the current climate; attempts to support our personhood rather than our livelihoods as workers have been short-sighted and half baked. “Essential” jobs are those in which the laborer cannot afford to stay home, and their employers are not willing to lose funds over lost hours. Rampant disregard for the safety of healthcare workers – nay, any worker who interacts with others – has proven that those most invested in the system have lost sight of their humanity. Never before has it been so obvious, at least to me, that the face of American kindness and hospitality is very shallow, indeed. On top of it all, if we are not employed, our ability to even get a yearly checkup is jeopardized, let alone get intubated or, god forbid, vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the CDC puts the percentage of infected commercial workers at 7.8%; the same percentage as public health workers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/covid-data/covidview/index.html&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. The Washington Post writes that in the older population which has aged into Medicare, those who are poor enough to also qualify for Medicaid are four times more likely to contract the virus &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/income-emerges-as-a-major-predictor-of-coronavirus-infections-along-with-race/2020/06/22/9276f31e-b4a3-11ea-a510-55bf26485c93_story.html&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;. There is a direct link between class and safety. In a system that only exists because of the existence of these classes, it becomes apparent where the values of this structure lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see this happening on a smaller scale. Let’s talk about the way the CSU Athletics Department attempted to cover up the COVID-19 symptoms spiking among football players. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coloradoan.com/story/news/2020/08/04/colorado-state-university-athletes-say-administration-covering-up-coronavirus-health-threats/5572625002/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; At the expense of student health (both the players and the rest of the CSU student body), the institution chose to value the labor its student athletes provide – incidentally, the same labor that supports the Department’s $24,000,000 yearly income &lt;a href=&#34;https://csurams.com/documents/2019/1/21/FY18_NCAA_Report.pdf&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; – over the personhood and bodily safety of the institute’s population. Had the university president not stepped in to address the issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coloradoan.com/story/news/2020/08/06/colorado-state-university-hires-firm-husch-blackwell-investigate-athletic-department-covid-19/3314603001/&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, it is not hard to imagine it would have continued well into the school year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us who embrace their work and identify with it were the ones who protested earlier this summer for their right to go back to work. More common than this, however, was the population of (white) protesters who were fighting for their right to see others return to work—the aestheticians, servers, and other customer service employees. In this demanding sacrifice, I see how the individualistic nature of America’s day-to-day politics has failed us. The labor provided by these people—the haircuts, and meals, and cocktails—is more valuable than their safety. The protestors say, I want them to be able to earn a living. They do not say, I will protect them so they can keep on living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which, I suppose, is one way to cope with the knowledge that the pandemic is short-circuiting the country. I can understand them. By seventh grade I was also basing success and personal value and fulfillment on money. I will continue to do this to some degree for as long as I live here – there’s no getting around the fact that it would take drastic life changes to exit the society I criticize. Shit talking and making plans to exit are also another way to process, considering the direction things are going. I hear there are old houses that need fixing in Nova Scotia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we supposed to accept that our moral personhood is on hold during an indefinite pandemic? Can we? Regardless of which party takes or retains office in November, we can rest assured that as long as America is the sort of ‘cutthroat’ capitalist that makes European ‘cuddly’ capitalism look impossibly generous, the pandemic is going to continue to threaten—or expose—how we are valued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/blog/post/marx-covid1.jpg#blog&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have any way to properly answer or even address this sort of issue. What I can say is, I think this serves as a call for us to re-address our social contract. If you are outraged, tip the servers who have no choice of staying home. Buy your artist friend’s work, commission the editors, support the locals. In our communities, it is worthwhile to spot who is trying to translate their own personal value into their creations. I can say with confidence that is the sort of business to support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than that, though, don’t ever forget to express appreciation and value beyond what others can do for you. Show gratitude that your sister is here, because your sister is here and for no other reason. It’s easy to forget that we don’t owe each other productivity. Thank your local bookstore for closing and keeping themselves safe. Call your friends and your acquaintances and your upstairs neighbors and your coworkers and the postman. I think a lot of times we forget that there are many ways to show that we still value each other for our senses of humor, our passion, our weekly dog playdates. Protest, yes, but also send a letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, I enrolled in a women’s studies class which addressed race, sexuality, disparity, ability. We sat in a horseshoe-shaped conglomeration of desks and looked at each other when we talked about how we could possibly help in a climate that felt so inexhaustibly hateful. After the conversations about good trouble, and educating others, and listening, the professor said, take care of yourself. Take care of others. Success can be measured differently. She was quoting Audre Lorde:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Caring for myself is not self-indulgence, it is self-preservation, and that is an act of political warfare.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Intersectional Notes; Readings on the Subject:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.democracynow.org/2019/8/13/ibram_x_kendi_class_race_capitalism&#34;&gt;Ibram X Kendi on Capitalism, Racism, &amp;amp; Anti-Racism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urban.org/urban-wire/new-data-suggest-covid-19-widening-housing-disparities-race-and-income&#34;&gt;COVID-19 is Widening Racial and Economic Housing Disparities &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ravishly.com/2015/03/06/radical-act-self-care-black-women-feminism&#34;&gt;Evette Dionne on Black Self-Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2020/03/23/coronavirus-spread-poverty-covid-19-stimulus-column/2899411001/&#34;&gt;Poverty and COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resources that Might Be Relevant Right Now: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.internationaldisabilityalliance.org/content/covid-19-and-disability-movement&#34;&gt;https://www.internationaldisabilityalliance.org/content/covid-19-and-disability-movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://naacp.org/coronavirus/coronavirus-resources/&#34;&gt;https://naacp.org/coronavirus/coronavirus-resources/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hhs.gov/coronavirus/community-based-testing-sites/index.html&#34;&gt;https://www.hhs.gov/coronavirus/community-based-testing-sites/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://international.colostate.edu/isss/resources-for-international-students-scholars-during-the-covid-19-crisis/&#34;&gt;https://international.colostate.edu/isss/resources-for-international-students-scholars-during-the-covid-19-crisis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding “Ching Chong House” and Anti-Asian Racism in the Wake of COVID-19</title>
      <link>/blog/anti-asian-racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:16:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/anti-asian-racism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;regarding-ching-chong-house-and-anti-asian-racism-in-the-wake-of-covid-19&#34;&gt;Regarding “Ching Chong House” and Anti-Asian Racism in the Wake of COVID-19&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in July, a fake restaurant emerged on Instagram and Yelp. This fake restaurant was entitled “Ching Chong House” and had various racist menu items ranging from Corona cocktails to “Crispy Burnt Pug.” Although it is clear that this stunt is merely another in a long list of unfunny edgy shock humor devoid of any creativity or actual comedy, it is still worth examining given the social context we find ourselves in. As of July 2, 2020—just one day after this fake business first posted—&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/anti-asian-american-hate-incidents-up-racism/&#34;&gt;2,120 anti-Asian hate incidents had been reported between March and June&lt;/a&gt;. The number is almost certainly higher now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially planned to censor the title of the restaurant in this post, but ultimately realized that the power of it was something I did not want to dilute or obfuscate. Reclaiming slurs is not new amongst marginalized communities, but this is clearly something different—this is meant to evoke taunting and give permission to be hateful under the guise of comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At risk of relying too much on my heritage to inform my blog posts, I still feel like it is appropriate to disclose that I am part Korean and that while this rhetoric obviously has emotional consequences, it also has material consequences. I am already keenly aware that the growing anti-Chinese sentiment in this country has made my family less safe. I have seen the contemptuous stares people give my mother and have watched as she has become more and more guarded whenever she leaves the house. Of course, even those with no personal ties to Asian communities can clearly see the racist nature of these comments and grasp their harm, but there is often a more intimate and acute anger that one feels when their own community is targeted. Still, if you need more to get angry, there are other cases far more severe, such as when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/coronavirus-bullies-attack-asian-teen-los-angeles-accusing-him-of-having-coronavirus/&#34;&gt;an Asian student was accused of having COVID-19 and subsequently assaulted and hospitalized&lt;/a&gt; or when &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc7ny.com/wheres-your-(expletive)-mask-asian-woman-attacked-in-nyc/6003396/&#34;&gt;a Korean student in Manhattan was grabbed by the hair and punched in the face and accused of being a COVID-19 carrier&lt;/a&gt;. There are many similar stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a moment swelling with racial tension and rising xenophobic rhetoric—specifically Sinophobic rhetoric that has been espoused by both the Democratic Party and the Republican Party—this is an accelerant. Normalizing this brand of racism gives permission to the next person to do the same. The account owners attempted to excuse their behavior by proclaiming they themselves are Asian and that this is merely situational comedy. Putting aside that this “humor” is on par with 8th graders who think slurs and Szechuan sauce are the height of comedy and the fact these people are probably not Asian (and are likely attempting to avoid culpability with a vague and unprovable statement), their intentions and races are ultimately irrelevant. Internalized and intracommunity racism are a demonstrably real phenomenon and your race does not exempt you from perpetuating racism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although our politicians’ rhetoric is quickly devolving into blatant xenophobia and still insists “China Virus” comments are in good faith, we must hold ourselves to a higher standard. I am deeply disaffected by our governmental representatives and find that I no longer view them as lighthouses in a vast sea of mere citizens. If anything, the way elected officials have handled COVID-19—from granting the stock market more funds than civilians, to refusing to freeze rent, to offering a measly and incompetently handled stimulus check, to turning both parties into anti-China propaganda machines—has further convinced me we are living in a dystopian hellscape that we cannot trust them to rescue us from. We must, as civilians, be better than the people who are representing us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I urge CSU’s President Joyce McConnell to take strong action against any students or staff involved—it is suspected that the architects of the account are CSU students and at least 13 students and 1 staff member have been confirmed to be following the account. I have, in the past, found CSU’s response to racism incredibly underwhelming and gestural, but I have noticed a shift in tone that no longer defends these actions as freedom of speech and insists it is impossible to punish racist students. If there is truly a “zero tolerance policy” on racism at CSU, there must be consequences—if there aren’t, then you quite literally have a “tolerance policy” on racism. I sincerely hope these students are held accountable in ways more than rhetorical. Their prank is making people less safe. If that isn’t grounds for dismissal, I’m not sure what is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Asian/Pacific American Cultural Center at CSU released a statement on their website &lt;a href=&#34;https://apacc.colostate.edu/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Collegian has written an in-depth article &lt;a href=&#34;https://collegian.com/2020/07/category-news-fake-restaurant-listing-perpetuates-racism-towards-asian-communities/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more on the history and usage of the slur ‘Ching Chong,’ you can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2014/07/14/330769890/how-ching-chong-became-the-go-to-slur-for-mocking-east-asians&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reopening Schools</title>
      <link>/blog/reopening-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:13:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/reopening-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-schools-reopening-will-look-like-for-teachers&#34;&gt;What Schools Reopening Will Look Like for Teachers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haley Arnold, Publications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks, millions of students will be returning to school for the fall. Despite the current COVID-19 pandemic with cases on the rise again, most schools are planning on having at least some in-person learning. For parents, this requires them to make a tough decision on whether or not to send their children to school- or to opt for online only options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online learning would prevent the students from contracting and spreading the virus, which would protect others-quality online education, it is hard to get the same results as in-person teaching. To make matters more confusing, many parents are going back to work and cannot be home to assist their children or afford childcare. This will be a hard decision for many families and there is a large population that will be affected by schools re-opening that do not get a choice. If teachers want to keep their job and get paid their salary, they must return to school in the Fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average age of the 3.7 million teachers in the U.S. is 42 years old, and a third of teachers are over 50 years old which makes them high risk. 92% of COVID-19 deaths have been in adults 55 years and older. These are scary statistics for many teachers and their families, and leave them with many unanswered questions. Not only will teachers be at risk, but their partners, their own children, parents, or others that they are in contact with will be at risk of coming in contact with the virus. The many bus drivers, janitors, cafeteria workers and other staff it takes to keep a school running will also be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help me answer some questions about the current positions teachers are in, I was able to interview a teacher from a small town in Colorado. For the sake of her privacy and the unknown about the next school year, I will be keeping her name and school district anonymous. As of right now, her school&amp;rsquo;s plan is as follows; “Our school district will have schools open as normal with in-person learning, regular school hours, Monday through Friday starting August 24th. Parents also have the option of having their children do 100% online school at home from an outside source. Masks will be required at school for adults, but only for children 11 and older. Social distancing of at least t is recommended, but It’s up to . No precautious health checks at the schools will be performed. No COVID tests will be required for staff or students before they start back. A school or classroom may go to remote learning for 3-14 days if a student tests positive for the virus. Teachers will continue with teaching their students remotely over zoom from home and will get paid as if they were in the classroom in these instances and will return to the classroom after the 3-14 days. With the school being in a small town, the teachers there are paid much less than some of the bigger districts, and there are very few businesses that provide tax-based funding for the schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If staff get sick, they “will have to use their sick days and may not file for worker’s compensation.” “The district is not liable for any COVID sickness or deaths in staff or students.” Both herself and her partner are in the high-risk category for contracting the virus, and currently, “there is no online teaching option for high-risk teachers.” Her and her partner have manysick days saved up that they have accumulated over years of teaching. They are currently waiting to hear back on if they can use those sick days to take a leave until there is a vaccine. However, many teachers don’t have any sick days saved up, so if they don’t feel safe going back to 100% in-person learning. In addition, she explains “Some teachers have quit because either they or someone in their immediate family is at high risk for COVID complications.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in a small town might sound safer than a big city; however, that doesn’t mean there are no cases. The idea that the virus is a hoax is common there, and there is a large anti-mask movement. In addition, “some of the residents have been vacationing in high COVID case states over the summer without taking measures to protect themselves from the virus.” When they and their families come back and return to school, it’s possible they could have brought it with them. Their school also has tiny windows and no air conditioning, making it difficult to create any airflow, and there is a chance that many students and adults will not take the safety precautions seriously in a town that does not strongly believe in protecting their residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we creep closer and closer to the start of the school year, teachers are anxiously waiting to hear back on decisions regarding what they can do for their own safety, and many are wondering what they will do for income if they must quit. It is not uncommon for teachers to be overlooked in situations like this. Our country is often hesitant to acknowledge the hard work teachers put into their job- and forgets to provide teachers fair resources and opportunities. Teachers play a crucial role in the development of our country and teaching students who can go on to help solve issues like this pandemic, yet the concern for their safety and income is not a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Black Allyship as a Non-Black Person of Color</title>
      <link>/blog/navigating-black-allyship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 19:30:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/navigating-black-allyship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-black-allyship-as-a-non-black-person-of-color&#34;&gt;Navigating Black Allyship as a Non-Black Person of Color&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herman Luis Chavez, Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-Black people of color, it can be difficult to navigate allyship with the Black community, especially for those who are only just now beginning to educate themselves on Black justice. This article provides an introduction to the first steps and best practices you can take to be a better ally for Black folk in the U.S. as a non-black person of color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allyship is a complicated ordeal, especially for non-Black people of color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the recent nation-wide demonstrations in response to the disproportionate effects of police brutality on Black communities, many white individuals have found themselves inspired to seek education that confronts their white privilege, that exposes the history of white supremacy in the U.S., and that lays bare the realities of racial disparities in police systems. Yet, communities of non-Black people of color have been either silent or selfish, such as the hesitancy to join in protests or the reports of &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesource.com/2020/06/03/new-yorks-dyckman-dominicans-oust-protestors-from-the-neighborhood/&#34;&gt;Hispanic neighborhoods ousting protesters in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorism is prominent in Hispanic communities, where we see darker-skinned Latinos are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/07/02/hispanics-with-darker-skin-are-more-likely-to-experience-discrimination-than-those-with-lighter-skin/&#34;&gt;more likely to experience racial discrimination&lt;/a&gt; and are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5104999/&#34;&gt;more likely to experience worse mental and physical health&lt;/a&gt;. A preference for lighter skin in Latino communities often &lt;a href=&#34;https://imdiversity.com/villages/hispanic/why-understanding-colorism-within-the-latino-community-is-so-important/&#34;&gt;begins in the household&lt;/a&gt;, with families praising lighter-skinned children and treating darker-skinned children worse, often calling them racially charged terms such as “indio” or “prieto” that teaches a distinction between lighter skin and darker skin. Latinos carry this with them in the way they treat Black people. The racial ambiguity of Latinos make it all the more difficult to deconstruct their relationship with racism both in and out of the Hispanic community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in Asian communities, a preference for lighter skin complicated their relationship with Black justice. This white preference is often &lt;a href=&#34;https://thediplomat.com/2019/12/where-does-the-asian-obsession-with-white-skin-come-from/&#34;&gt;made explicit through health products or procedures&lt;/a&gt;, like those from Thailand, that promote a change in image in pursuit of lighter skin. The k-pop musical genre that is immensely popular in the U.S. is largely based off of Black musical styles—a sign of cultural appropriation—and the powerful k-pop industry has &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/rethinking-the-k-pop-industrys-silence-during-the-black-lives-matter-movement-141025&#34;&gt;largely stayed silent in the wake of Black Lives Matter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These instances of racial preference in non-Black communities have very real consequences for Black communities. We should not forget Hmong-American Tou Thao’s complicit behaviour as Derek Chauvin knelt on George Floyd’s neck, when he stood nearby and ignored Floyd’s repeated pleas to breathe. It is difficult for those of us who identify as non-Black people of color to acknowledge colorism or racism in our own communities that are already discriminated against in American society, but it is vital to deconstruct our concepts of race to support Black individuals who suffer the most systemic violence and oppression in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… how do we do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step One: Understand that to be an ally, you must be actively anti-racist.&lt;/strong&gt; This means moving past being simply “not racist,” where your complicity allows racism to continue in yourself and in those around you. The National Museum of African American History &amp;amp; Culture’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmaahc.si.edu/learn/talking-about-race/topics/being-antiracist&#34;&gt;guide to being anti-racist&lt;/a&gt; says it best: “Being antiracist results from a conscious decision to make frequent, consistent, equitable choices daily.” This means challenging racism whenever you see it, whether in yourself or in others; it also means incorporating anti-racism into your daily life, such as dedicating yourself to sign at least one petition, read at least one article, or contact at least one elected official every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Two: Acknowledge that we are on both sides of the issue, and that is valid.&lt;/strong&gt; On one hand, people of color do experience racism everyday in this country, from the anti-immigration rhetoric used against Hispanic individuals to the anti-Asian rhetoric that has grown out of the COVID-19 pandemic. However, on the other, we do experience privilege due to the lighter color of our skin, and we are not as systematically oppressed as Black people. We must recognize that our own racial and ethinic suffering is valid while also understanding the importance of supporting Black communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Three: Confront your own anti-Black tendencies and those in your household.&lt;/strong&gt; Does your family call you “moreno” and prefer your lighter-skinned sibling? Do you still subconsciously cross the street when you see a Black person walking in your direction? Take some time to take stock as to how racist rhetoric, no matter how small, has manifested itself in your daily life. We must understand when we have been programmed for racism and actively counter those measures. This is especially important to do at home, to ensure that we don’t pass along those dangerous perspectives to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Four: Empathize.&lt;/strong&gt; We need to understand that the loss of Black lives are not just names or numbers on your old college friend’s Instagram story; these are human beings, with lives and relationships like us who remember them. By understanding the humanity of the suffering of Black families, where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/content/116/34/16793&#34;&gt;1 in 1,000 Black men can be expected to die at the hands of police brutality&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justicepolicy.org/news/8775&#34;&gt;whose children are funneled through the school-to-prison pipeline&lt;/a&gt;, we open ourselves to how necessary it is to become an ally in anti-racism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Five: Education.&lt;/strong&gt; Deconstruct your relationship with whiteness and power by centering the Black experience in narrative, qualitative, and quantitative manners. Read books by Black authors, listen to podcasts that break down Black history, study articles on systemic racism in police systems. By spending the time acquiring knowledge on the Black experience, you become better equipped to challenge your own viewpoints and to educate others. Here’s a starting point: go back to each of the links throughout this article and read them. Next step? Visit the end of this list for some more resources to get you started. By simply reading every link in this article, you are already taking an important step in anti-racism and supporting Black communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also put all of these steps together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the time to listen about their stories from those who knew them. While it may be uncomfortable, confronting the humanity of the victims of police brutality allow us to open our hearts more to understanding the experience that these communities endure. I have been attending a weekly webinar titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://jlukewood.com/black-minds-matter/&#34;&gt;Black Minds Matter&lt;/a&gt;, a public course intended to raise the national consciousness about issues affecting Black children in education (you can attend the last three sessions; they’re coming up now!), where academics, educators, and guest speakers discuss the importance of valuing Black knowledge at all levels of our education system. In our last session, we heard from Gwen Carr, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/16/nyregion/eric-garner-case-death-daniel-pantaleo.html&#34;&gt;Eric Garner&lt;/a&gt;’s mother. Here are a few quotes that Carr mentioned about Garner, which gave the audience a depth we couldn’t understand only from a name and a statistic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The family always wanted him at the functions, he was the life of the party.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I stopped them from picking on him, and I brought him home for dinner.” Carr recalls Garner saying this to her when she came home to find him with a classmate who had been bullied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘Mom look! I did it, I got 100% attendance,’ and I said, ‘You did that?’ and he said, ‘no mom, you did. You got me up every morning.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was a strong student. He didn’t have too many problems in school with his classmates, the teachers talked highly about him, and they said that he was a person who if you confronted him, he would face it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By attending the Black Minds Matter webinars, for only 90 minutes a week, I am taking action for education that stimulates empathy and it turns allows me to be more successful when I engage in anti-racist work with myself and others. This is one of many examples of the type of actionable items you can take to support the Black community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a difficult step to take, but an important one to bring about racial equality for everyone. By reframing our relationship with racism, becoming anti-racist, and supporting Black communities, we begin the change that breaks away at the strength of racism throughout our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/0Bz011IF2Pu9TUWIxVWxybGJ1Ync&#34;&gt;A Google Drive folder with readings, videos, speeches, music, and more that focus on Black history and liberation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oyc.yale.edu/african-american-studies/afam-162&#34;&gt;Free Yale Online Course: African American History: From Emancipation to the Present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.library.georgetown.edu/antiracism&#34;&gt;Georgetown Anti-Racism Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://libguides.usc.edu/c.php?g=756583&amp;amp;p=5976573&#34;&gt;USC Anti-Racist Pedagogy Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://libraryguides.saic.edu/popup/antiracism&#34;&gt;School of the Art Institute of Chicago Anti-Racism and Black Lives Matter Virtual Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blacklivesmatters.carrd.co/#petitions&#34;&gt;Petitions to sign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.humanitiesamped.com/uploads/8/9/3/8/89385582/colorism_101_easy_reference_and_resource_for_educators.pdf&#34;&gt;Colorism 101 for Educators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on allies and space on Tik Tok and Instagram</title>
      <link>/blog/reflecting-on-allies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 19:22:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/reflecting-on-allies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflecting-on-allies-and-space-on-tik-tok-and-instagram&#34;&gt;Reflecting on allies and space on Tik Tok and Instagram&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Dunn, Art Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media has acted as a primary source of information, education, and organization throughout the Black Lives Matter movement since the its inception in 2013. It has been a platform for people to share and promote speakers, books, funds and organizations. Mass participation can create a sense of unity, community, and wide-reaching support, but done ingenuously, it can run the risk of being noise. Adding to a discussion doesn’t always mean you’re listening, and it’s easy to share recommending book lists without any intention to read them for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way that we, white allies, engage with social media during times of political organization - but even during our everyday lives -  has implications. Many of us are aware of these implications - how am I showing my support? How are the posts I’m sharing signaling that I deeply care about this cause? (And, the nagging fear of every white person, “How do I prove to people I’m not racist? How do I prove it to myself?”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we post and interact with social media, I think we should also have something very important in mind: What space am I taking up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Instagram Blackout at the end of May proved a necessity for this final question, as the trend of posting a black square in solidarity ended up clogging up valuable resource hashtags and entire feeds. Even though it did not replace any of this information, it essentially buried it. (What is important to note is that the Instagram Blackout, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/02/style/instagram-blackout.html&#34;&gt;which has been planned by two Black women in the music marketing industry, Jamila Thomas and Brianna Agyemang&lt;/a&gt;, was meant to be a focused and industry-specific response to the movement due to the huge influence Black culture has on pop music. What it became was the unfortunate result of the movement being co-opted by white allies with little understanding of the original intention.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In social media, space is valuable. When we post, we take up space on someone’s feed. As feeds constantly change to allow popular posts to float to the top, social media algorithms are designed to promote posts that seem valuable and popular. The most promoted creators and posts are often white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December, the social media version of a child star, TikTok, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/1/21277505/tiktok-black-creators-censorship-algorithm-donation-diversity-council&#34;&gt;admitted that its algorithm&lt;/a&gt; prioritized videos from white, thin, cisgender and conventionally attractive creators. Creators who were non-white, disabled, queer or fat were suppressed and would be pushed down the line of videos because they were “vulnerable to cyberbullying”. And it’s not just the creator’s appearance. Tiktok’s censorship seems to miraculously pass over the trends that seem to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.insider.com/tiktok-continues-to-have-problems-with-racist-videos-2020-5&#34;&gt;encourage racist statements and rhetoric&lt;/a&gt; and instead pick up and shadowban videos with the tags #acab and #fuckthepolice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Malcolm X’s birthday on May 19th, TikTok creators banded together to protest censorship in a platform-wide blackout with the hashtag #ImBlack or #ImBlackMovement. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/19/us/tiktok-black-lives-matter-trnd/index.html&#34;&gt;Organized by BLM Utah founder Lex Scott&lt;/a&gt;, the blackout encouraged Black creators and allies to change their icons to the raised black fist, to follow at least one new Black creator, to unfollow all creators opposed to the movement, and to like, share, and comment on Black creator’s videos in order to drive up their engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the black square movement on Instagram, this movement put emphasis on creating a space for Black voices. Ally support was not measured by adding to the social media space but by providing unseen support through engagement. Allies joined the Black community to comment, like and share videos to drive up engagement specifically, and exclusively, for Black creators. Just for that day, ONLY Black creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TikTok blackout was a success. Not only did users report their feeds being flooded with only Black content for the day, but they noticed a shift in their algorithm afterward. My sister, who participated in the blackout, said that she saw a noticeable rise in Black creators on her FYP, and that some of the accounts she was following mentioned they had noticed higher sustained engagement afterwards, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blackout was focused and targeted onto fighting the racist algorithm, the institution itself. The point of the event was not simply a show of support, but a specific raising up of marginalized voices. Hearing about the specific focus of the blackout, and it’s subsequent success pushed me to reflect on how i use social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the way I use social media take up space? Am I posting a black square that shows support but clogs up vital tags and feed space, or is it a comment that heightens engagement on a creator’s post? Both actions have similar intentions: white allies want to show solidarity and support. But we can see that some actions take space from others, while some actions create space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well intentions should still undergo internal criticism and debate before being expressed. Many creators on social media made BLM-themed objects to sell in order to fundraise money to donate to the cause. Beauty gurus posted black-owned makeup haul videos. These are both supportive and helpful, but they still take up space as interesting ways to deserve some evaluation. In most cases, seeing fundraisers by broke college students doing everything they can to help is very admirable. But there are other stores that give me pause. Why do some white creators choose to co-opt black iconography and messaging in order to help rather than pointing their followers to preexisting Black artists who make similar products? Why don’t makeup artists facilitate more story takeovers from Black makeup artists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have good intentions, and I’m not saying these responses are wrong. They are forms of support and solidarity. But we, as white people on social media, have got to start being more self-critical of the space we take up on social media. Who could be there instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, boost engagement for Black creators. Comment, share, like. On every post, create reengagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17 years ago: the last Brood X</title>
      <link>/blog/brood-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:18:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/brood-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;17-years-ago-the-last-brood-x&#34;&gt;17 years ago: the last Brood X&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molly Flood, Communications Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spring of 2004 raised two kinds of children. I, a proud four and a half year old, spent my time playing outside with toys and picking apart the lawn while a swath of angsty 17 year olds also emerged into the open air, ready to scream all summer long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new insect  invasion added a whole new level of mischief  to my summer days as I collected my cicada friend&amp;rsquo;s empty exoskeletons and hung them all over my sister&amp;rsquo;s coat when she wasn’t looking. I imagine the teen cicadas rolled their five eyes as my immaturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year 2004 was a particularly strange one for these ancient creatures to enter the eastern United States. This was the time that the human population stumbled into the digital age and pop culture began to viralize events. The cicadas waited seventeen years to emerge into the future, but entered into an America that was obsessed with internet culture and paid no attention to their marvelous arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bold Brood X popped their heads out of the ground to the background noise of limelight celebrities making their place in the world. Paris Hilton’s “that’s hot” and Donald Trump’s “your fired” coexisted peacefully in the world of reality TV, far from the whitehouse. Brood X played their own recognizable phrase: a high pitched buzzing reaching 100 decibels, that masked Trump’s and Hilton’s voices blaring from the living rooms of America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the cicadas lived their short lives to the fullest back in 2004, Facebook was taking over the internet and shaping the American reality. Through the eyes locked into Facebook in 2004, American’s learned that Martha Stewart would be spending time in prison while memes about the newly released Napoleon Dynamite spread awkward core through the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teen cicadas,who rebelliously dug up from their subterranean homes, shouted their last thoughts and perished in a matter of weeks. In their short lifespans, they  saw America through the lens of it’s awkward emergence into the internet, social media, and pop culture buzz. 2004’s brood’s screams masked the worlds of Trump and Zuckerberg’s America to enjoy a peaceful summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their children enter a new world, one that only the most perceptive eye would have guessed would exist. What slogan and internet personalities will they rival with? As the proud children of 2004’s Brood X emerge from the earth, don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised when we see an abnormal amount of exoskeletons looming on parked Tesla&amp;rsquo;s as this year&amp;rsquo;s Brood comes for Musk’s America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The commodification of Black pain: Why &#39;White Fragility&#39; falls short</title>
      <link>/blog/white-fragility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 19:46:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/white-fragility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-commodification-of-black-pain-why-white-fragility-falls-short&#34;&gt;The commodification of Black pain: Why &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;White Fragility&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; falls short&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of yet another reckoning with the antiblackness that permeates every corner of the U.S., many people have scrambled for ways to make sense of it all. For some, it is a familiar topic of conversation, one that has shaped their entire life. For others, it is an abstract knowledge they may only be exploring for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these individuals, self-education has become a common prescription. Social media users who are more well versed in the topic of antiblack racism have curated various reading lists with recommended reading for nonblack people. One title has popped up in several of these posts, often floating to the top of the list. I recognized it from when it hit the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; Best Seller List in 2018 and stayed there for over a year. It stirred some controversy then, but it has since reemerged in the wake of the George Floyd protests, once again becoming a best seller, highly recommended and rated on Amazon and endlessly passed around on my Facebook feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is called “White Fragility: Why It’s So Hard for White People to Talk About Racism,” written by a White academic named Robin DiAngelo. You’ve likely heard of this book before—or, at the very least, have heard of its central thesis. Her primary assertion is that White people are inherently complicit in racism and that they must do work to dismantle this, defining resistance to this concept “white fragility” or “white defensiveness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not the target audience for this book and withheld critique because I did not have a strong opinion of it. I’m mixed AfroLatine and thought there was no reason for me to read a simplified version of racism for reluctant White people, but as it became more and more famous, I noticed insidious things about it. Reading it validated some of my more cynical analyses of the narcissism of neoliberal elite establishments, but it also deeply confused me. It appears I was not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The critiques of the book vary. One common critique is some variation of “racism is not that bad, and I’m upset at being implicated.” I view this critique as fundamentally absurd, ahistorical, and demonstrably false. Another critique, primarily presented on the Left, is that DiAngelo uses corporate framing to offer a prescriptive non-solution to a problem that could be more effectively solved by addressing workers’ rights and establishing socialized policy. The idea is that class solidarity supersedes racial solidarity and that to proclaim otherwise is playing into corporate division tactics and identity politics. The Left has very scant media representation and, perhaps predictably, the voices that have succeeded have been almost exclusively White. It is not shocking to me, then, that their critique correctly analyzes DiAngelo’s poor framing and conflict of interest but fails to diagnose the real pervasiveness and seriousness of antiblackness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem with “White Fragility” is that is reads as a self-congratulatory Racism 101 course that centers the White experience above all and sanitizes the experience of people of color, especially Black people—ironically, likely to be more palatable for a White audience. The book is incredibly repetitive and condescending, entirely satisfied in its commodification of racism in the U.S. and once you realize how much money she’s made from this book and how much it has brought her fame, it feels openly exploitative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centering the White Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DiAngelo is a White woman. A White author being the primary spokesman for people of color would seem to undermine the ethos of the book, which often emphasizes listening to us. There is a strong narcissistic streak to the entire narrative; it is all about White people, even as we are being finger wagged at about how we leave people of color out of conversations about their own oppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear plenty about white privilege, white fragility, white tears, white guilt, etc. But we hear very little from or about people of color’s experiences outside of being oppression boards. She offers few positive stories about people of color—instead, every interaction regarding racism is combative and confrontational. There’s also a creepiness to the way in which nonwhite people are reduced to props in the backdrop of White people’s journey towards enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an incredible irony in watching groups of rich White elites argue amongst themselves about racism. There is even more irony is watching the critique of these people come from other White people and watching their arguments still miss the point. It’s a bizarre reminder that we aren’t allowed to be the protagonist even in stories ostensibly about us. DiAngelo didn’t write about us. She wrote about White people’s feelings about us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Corporate Angle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is part of the Left critique of DiAngelo’s work that is actually quite prudent. DiAngelo fills her books with anecdotes of defensive workers she met during her stint as a corporate diversity trainer. She, bizarrely, appears to offer her advice as a corporate consultant without acknowledging this approach would be inappropriate with family and friends. She doesn’t appear to acknowledge this because she doesn’t realize it, which makes it even more concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prescribed lines come across as insincere and almost cartoonishly silly, furthering the impression that this is about optics and sounding woke rather than about effecting meaningful change. She also often paints coworkers as being the harbingers of inequality but fails to ever acknowledge the way corporations are plagued by systemic racism. To eliminate racism from the workplace would require a reckoning with the capitalist structures that have historically disenfranchised people of color, particularly Black and brown people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She even often frames racism as…microaggressions in the workplace. Sure, this happens and yes, it is inappropriate and negatively affects people of color. However, it betrays a bias in which it is clear she believes the more overt types of racism—lynching, hate crimes, wrongful termination, being denied housing, poor access to medical care, higher mortality rates, etc.—are either less important or less common than corporate microaggressions. We don’t need to protect ourselves from a lawsuit. We need to foster more empathy for people of color. Now, more than ever, what we need is for White people to see the humanity of Black people. This book does not give us the tools to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Political Divide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of what makes this book stand out and, I believe, part of why this book was so instinctively rejected by the Left is because there is a huge ideological rift between the Democratic Party and progressives. DiAngelo incorrectly defines “progressives,” couching it into the term “White progressives,” which feels as though it is intentionally avoiding Martin Luther King Jr.’s naming of “the White moderate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through subtleties like that, it becomes apparent that DiAngelo has a political ideology that is notoriously infantilizing and condescending towards people of color and is diametrically opposed to the politics of racial justice groups, which are typically Leftist in nature. The &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; is a moderate outlet with a clear ideological bend, and it feels like no coincidence that this book was widely covered by the publication and then began increasing in sales. To be entirely fair, the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and other more moderate outlets have praised Black literature and showcased it, helping to garner attention, but they can be problematic vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest critiques of White moderates is that they are often incredibly complicit in systems of racism and inequality, but instead of addressing these issues head-on, they offer strong rhetoric that they do not practice nor seem to truly believe. This political divide is, despite popular belief, not a new one. Again, Martin Luther King Jr. criticized White moderates, and although DiAngelo often says the “correct” answer, her rhetoric is insidious in its insincerity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letting White Academics Set the Conversation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we offer academics a disproportionately large amount of credibility, we allow them to set the tone of the conversation. Perhaps this would be appropriate in the case of something like neurobiology or electrical engineering, but when discussing race issues, particularly the systemic kind, academia is hardly the authority. Colleges uphold and perpetuate systemic racism in complicated, nuanced ways, which is not the primary topic of this piece, but remains incredibly relevant. When considering how this book became so famous, one must consider the systems of power that allowed a White academic to set the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This critique is substantially reduced with Black academics and other nonwhite academics, but even then, the discourse can be divorced from material realities or become corroded by stewing in a context that is implicitly hostile towards antiracism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offering No Solutions—What was the Goal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DiAngelo very conspicuously offers no solutions as to how to actually improve the material conditions of Black people. She only appears to encourage self-flagellation to absolve oneself of any accidental racism while engaging in said racism. &lt;em&gt;Feeling guilty is centering your fragile white feelings&lt;/em&gt;, she insists, as she continues intentionally provoking guilt and centering the White experience. She paints the reader into a corner by taking the possibility of criticism off the table and gives them nothing but the recommendation they attend her pricey racial sensitivity seminars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes across as being provocative for the sake of being provocative and really, the idea is a self-defeating one. The theory of White fragility is fundamentally unprovable because any critique of it is an apparent confirmation of itself. It does not encourage dialogue or move the needle—it simply alienates for the sake of establishing one’s own moral superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, this is a book that reviews the same concepts over and over without offering any suggestions on how to help advance the liberation of nonwhite people. It doesn’t seem interested in endearing itself to the reader and is, in fact, openly hostile towards the reader, who is ostensibly trying to unlearn their racism. It is difficult to believe her goal is to convert the layman. She simply presents her narrow realm of corporate moderate ideology that abstracts our experiences with racism to make White people feel guilty and buy her books so she can profit off our pain while talking about us like cardboard cutouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are to assume the goal is self-education, there are far better books written by authors of color which we can and should be reading instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-reading&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Black Lives Matter is the focal point of this newsletter and the framing I had in mind when critiquing “White Fragility,” I am recommending specifically Black pieces. Many Black liberation writers are Leftists, which comes across in their writings, and I strongly believe we need to reclaim that space on the Left. We must be able to discuss our lived experiences without it being erased as being mere identity politics. A great first step is getting truly educated and building genuine empathy for Black people. Here are some of cornerstone pieces that are actually written by Black people, many of whom were/are Black academics and/or activists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Are Prisons Obsolete?” – Angela Davis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The Fire Next Time” – James Baldwin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Ain&amp;rsquo;t I a Woman? Black Women and Feminism” – bell hooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The Autobiography of Malcolm X” – Malcolm X with Alex Haley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Report from the Bahamas” – June Jordan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Demarginalizing the Intersection of Race and Sex: A Black Feminist Critique of Antidiscrimination Doctrine, Feminist Theory and Antiracist Politics” – Kimberlé Williams Crenshaw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How to Be an Antiracist” – Ibram X. Kendi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Between the World and Me” – Ta-Nehisi Coates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t begin to scratch the surface and there are many pieces specifically on intersectionality, exploring queer Black identity, Black feminism, Black disability activism, capitalism’s effects on Black people, etc. At some point, we will hopefully explore some of these concepts in depth here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cicada’s Next Step: Our New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 18:46:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cicadas-next-step-our-new-blog&#34;&gt;Cicada’s Next Step: Our New Blog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay Serrano, Editorial Director&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, the world has changed in dramatic ways that have affected us all. CCM has had to contend with these changes and evolve, incorporating our original vision into a world that looks different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fostering community and engaging directly with our submitters, colleagues, and fellow travelers was our first unanimous goal&amp;ndash;we are still deeply committed to this core mission. This blog is our next step in achieving that goal, which now feels more imperative than ever given how difficult it has become to stay connected to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also be publishing a monthly newsletter with content curated by staff members and guests. This blog will function as a repository for this content and exist as a space for us to expand on broader ideals of ours as they relate to the art and literary worlds. We plan to use this platform to actively highlight current events and advocate for human rights and social justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first newsletter will be going live this Friday, July 24. As always, you can contact us at &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@cicadacreativemag.com&#34;&gt;info@cicadacreativemag.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. We’ll talk to you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay creative!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
